<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
	<title>Saads perfektewelt</title>
	<link>applethal.com</link>
	<description>Recent content in Blogs 🗒️ on Saads perfektewelt</description>
	<generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
	<language>en-us</language>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	
	
	<item>
		<title>My backlog of excuses</title>
		<link>applethal.com//localhost:1313/misc/backlog/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		
		<guid>//localhost:1313/misc/backlog/</guid>
		<description>
&lt;style&gt;
    a {
        text-decoration: none;
        color: yellow;
    }

    summary {
  list-style-type: &#39;⬇ &#39;;
}

details[open] &gt; summary {
  list-style-type: &#39;⬆ &#39;;
}

summary {
  background-color: #000000;
  color: white;
  padding: 10px;
  border-radius: 5px;
}

details[open] summary {border-radius: 5px 5px 0 0;}

details {
  background: #7F7F7F;
  border-radius: 5px;
}

/* extra styles */

* {box-sizing: border-box;}


article &gt; *:first-child {margin: 0;}
article &gt; * + * {margin: 0.75em 0 0 0;}
pre {color: white; background: #7F7F7F; padding: 1em; border-radius: 5px;}
article {padding: 10px; margin: 0;}
&lt;/style&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quite often, especially at night, I get creative ideas that burn me with passion. Sadly, the majority of such get stuck in a W.I.P. phase or -even worse- do not end up being executed. This is usually the case due to routine constraints, which is part of what makes an adult, my important priorities exhaust my energy and by extension my time, making it sometimes hard for me to consider the said ideas.

&lt;br&gt;
With proper planning, I may end up setting up the conditions necessary to start the execution, but sometimes I may reach obstacles that I can not heuristically solve. This post will list everything that I wished to make happen, it will contain its backstory, logistical excuses on why I could not (as of yet) execute the idea, and finally I will propose a process to help organise myself. This post will be actively updated as I keep getting ideas:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;Drawing a mixture of famous cartoon cats surfing together -- Status: Pending &lt;/summary&gt;
&lt;article&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Years ago and specifically in my third week in Ergotherapy, to train the dexterity of my hands and teach myself focus, the therapy woman proposed that we start with a painting activity. Back then, I haven&#39;t had any painting activities since more than a decade. I had little to no support on how to paint and I had no limit on what I could paint, the role of the woman was to aid me with my focus, nothing more nothing less. I used only my intuition to help myself on the creative part, I needed a background, and the easiest thing that I thought about was to take the blue colour and paint the sky, then I had the sudden idea to see if I can paint Garfield in a surfing notion, then few minutes later, I thought about adding Tom, from Tom &amp; Jerry, and as I was progressivly tinkering, I thought about adding more cats from other sources... And that&#39;s how the idea was born.. Except I could not finish the painting in time. I always to achieve this on a digital plane, and all what I would require is a tablette... And maybe some skills.  &lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;As of the 12th of Nov. 2024, I do not, sadless have the means to draw digitally at ease, as I can not relay on the mouse (even though I reckon its feasibility). The cheapest and best option I can do is to see if I can afford a graphical tablet, and reserve some time slots for this, maybe 2 hours max a week. The goal of that Ergotherapy exercise was to teach me that I don&#39;t have to do everything in one go anyways. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for the process, since getting a graphical tablet would be a long time investement, I think it would be best if I teach myself how to digitally paint using the tool and then start with the official execution. Time constraints should not matter here as I can reserve the 2 hours on the weekend and be happy about it. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/article&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;


</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
		<title>Skill transfer - GUI text editor to VIM</title>
		<link>applethal.com//localhost:1313/blog/st_vim/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		
		<guid>//localhost:1313/blog/st_vim/</guid>
		<description>
&lt;p&gt;Upon installing Arch linux on my Laptop, I had the thought of spending the summer writing articles in &lt;a
        href=&#34;https://www.vim.org/&#34;&gt; VIM&lt;/a&gt;, not only for stereotypical reasons, but to also improve my workflow, as I
    was told that using solely the keyboard and nothing but the keyboard has the magical effect on
    making your text editing endevours much faster. This statement resonates with me since I really enjoy using the
    keyboard more than the mouse. I fully recon that user interfaces are focused on making functions quite accessible,
    but in a text editing environment, I believe the keyboard has more speed potential. Vim
    capitalizes on this with its built-in macros setup; the trade-off lies in its learning curve... And ohhhh boy! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before trying to toy with VIM and since quite some time, my hands and arms were positioned in a way that reaches the
    mouse and the Ctrl, Shift and space keys; since these are the keys that I mostly use in my workflow. VIM takes this
    on a whole new level by making me use the entire keyboard, I am talking here
    about using keys that I would have never imagined myself using in a text editing environment. Funnily enough I had
    little to no difficulties getting used to the main navigation keys HJKL; I could easily transfer my dexterity from
    some video games, since the average game I played had me use the keyboard. This setup made me reconsider the
    position of my hands and arms, you might want to say that I started to feel like an octupus after using VIM for
    quite some time. I have never
    imagined myself for once being in a situation where using the ESC in a key combination, or caring about whether my
    CAPS lock is on in order to enable a macro.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Originally, I was going to write this article to document my learning journey while slowly updating it each time I
    learn something new. As of the writing of this blog post, I still have many macros to learn, but I can assure you
    that I became much faster at writing. So far I became efficient at jumping and deletion macros. The built-in &lt;a
        href=&#34;https://vimschool.netlify.app/introduction/vimtutor/&#34;&gt; Vimtutor&lt;/a&gt;, which can be accessed from the
    terminal at any time (Or online if you click the embedded link), is well made and I may even argue that it is quite
    faster than learning from a video. I began learning it on the 1st of May 2024; it is just a matter of building
    muscle memory at the end, and I have read articles
    from people claiming that once you start learning it, there is no going back. At the end of the road is the
    promising reward of efficient workflow, and honestly, it&#39;s worth it! Some of VIMs macros are intuitive if you are an
    english speaking, but some can still take some time. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I began incorporating VIM in writing emails through &lt;a href=&#34;https://neomutt.org/&#34;&gt;neomutt &lt;/a&gt; (I should write an
    article on that in the future), editing python scripts, typesetting my \(\LaTeX\) and writing these blog posts. From
    a quantitative perspective, you may say I became slightly faster at text editing by a couple of minutes. I can
    sight some room for improvement. What&#39;s more important is that I can transfer my skills from VIM to doing my chores
    on the terminal emulator, since getting used to the latter has also been proven to be much faster than using GUIs in
    some scenarios. I can only confirm victories here and no losses, it was worth my time.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;On defaults settings and since I am not using the numpad side of the keyboard, a choice between 60%-80% keyboard
    layouts is a good option. Their compact size and button placement looks as if it was made for this workflow,
    allowing my fingers to travel quickly and navigate through the keys with no issues. Of course you don&#39;t have to go
    for these
    types of keyboards, I myself would like to have the numpad installed just in case I am sitting in a non-working
    manner and just laying
    my arms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plugins wise, I still have not installed any plugins, and I think I should do so in the near future, especially if I
    am going to do some extensive coding on VIM, I will surely need something like a spell-checker. I want to stress out
    though, that I had a better experience learning it through the Vimtutor than &lt;a
        href=&#34;https://vim-adventures.com/&#34;&gt;Vimadventures &lt;/a&gt;. There are multiple
    resources and cheating-sheets out there to choose from. At the end of the day, VIM is an environment that
    strengthened my skills through practice, it takes time. Due to how well-designed Vimtutor is, my exercise routine
    revolved around going for 1 chapter at a time, and then writing code or walls of text to practice using what I have
    learned while also trying to keep my previously taught techniques in check. Trust the process! It will be funny if
    someone turns image editing into an activity that can be exercised using the keyboard efficiently better and faster
    than the mouse. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
		<title>My RoRo Arch linux theme</title>
		<link>applethal.com//localhost:1313/misc/theme/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		
		<guid>//localhost:1313/misc/theme/</guid>
		<description>

&lt;p&gt; I love colors that stem from the hot corner of the color spectrum, from red to purple. My mom used to forbid me
  from wearing these due to her associating these with femininity, constraining me to wear things that are &#34;men-coded&#34;.
  I fully comprehend where she is coming from, in fact, there is a study that backs up her opinions; for instance: Brown
  and purple are part of the problem solver color scheme, however, choosing to wear everything in purple and black gives
  an air of mystery. My closet contains a mixture of red, orange, pink and purple colors; I never thought about why I
  like these colors, but if you inspect
  the science of color psychology, I believe this combination should allow me to radiate myself as a person, after all, they say that 
  your looks tell a lot about you, though I wish this would not be the case, it sadly works. All in all, feel free to wear anything you want, as long as it ensures your comfort!
&lt;br&gt; Throughout time and space, I could not sadly find a perfect resource on color psychology, as each source I came across has some inconsistencies, something which prompts me to believe that this is one of those topics that are subject to the human perspective.
Because of this, I believe the best approach to deepen my comprehension on the matter is to try to explore characters that wear a similar colour pallete, and then explore their psychee&#39;s similarities. This article 
brings up one such character, one that I discovered by pure accident, and happens to be quite obscure from the public due to the niche nature of its media.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I love the character &lt;a href=&#34;https://azurestrikergunvolt.fandom.com/wiki/Lola&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt; from the gunvolt series, I
  liked the idea of a robotic figure that heals entities using her music. Her model&#39;s colour palette matches
  her energetic personality. You could say that I am her n°1 fan but I don&#39;t think I deserve the title. I wish if Inti&#39;s
  budget allowed them to expand upon her story, though if I could choose a favourite song, you might want to listen to
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=p9888TqD7xg&#34;&gt;Original chord &lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/sticker.png&#34;&gt;
  &lt;p style=&#34;color: #888; font-size: 14px;&#34;&gt;My RoRo sticker on my laptop&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Stickers of her character sadly do not appear to be available or even existing, and even if they did, I would presume
  them having prices that I can not afford. Both of these reasons pushed me into seeking some DYI solutions, which I
  ended up applying using &lt;a href=&#34;
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=eiUN7zUL0TE&#34;&gt;this tutorial &lt;/a&gt;. With 5€, a computer and some patience, I think an 1
  hour (Considering the trial and error I had to go through) was worth it, not only for the sake of the craft, but also
  to train my hands around its making.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Next is my Arch linux splash screen. I can hardly accept to use an OS without customizing its visual elements, even
  as a person who puts emphasis on minimalism. I was ready to go as far as spending hours in order to learn how to craft
  at least a splash screen, and so I decided to learn QML, which is essential for the making of splash screens without
  downloading any third-party software + honestly it was not that hard to deal with syntax wise. The splash screen has
  RoRo&#39;s combat pod form spinning with the following text beneath her: 「リミターカット！ フルドライブ！」, which is the
  exact line she says when activating her anthem mode. The text roughly says &#34;I shall cut my own limits! activating
  over-drive&#34;, a line which I deeply cherich before starting my productive endavours. The files of the splash screen can
  be found on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Applethal/RoRo-KDE&#34;&gt;my Github repo &lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;text-align: center; max-width: 100%; margin: auto;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;video style=&#34;width: 100%; height: auto;&#34; controls&gt;
    &lt;source src=&#34;//localhost:1313/RoRo.mp4&#34; type=&#34;video/mp4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/video&gt;
  &lt;p style=&#34;color: #888; font-size: 14px;&#34;&gt;RoRo splash screen&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In that same repo, you will find a wav file containing that exact same line. Back when I was working on this theme, I
  could not find any rips of dialogues across all the entries in the series. I took aprox. half a day to rip the files
  and clean them, only to extract one singular line of dialogues. The file can be used as a start-up sound that can be
  played upon logging in. That sound puts even more
  feelings to the system. &lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Lastly we have the Theme colors, which are reserved for the bars, windows and folders. Back when I was working on my
  own color scheme, I happen to have updated my system with some new files that broke the entire project, as it was
  dependent on many libraries that had to adapt to the new Plasma 6 environment. It took me 2 days to accept it, I then
  bit the bullet and chose to download a similar theme, which is honestly superior than mine. The colors theme in
  question here is &lt;a href=&#34;https://store.kde.org/p/1450418&#34;&gt;Strawberry Quartz &lt;/a&gt;, its color pallete matches exactly
  the one that RoRo. The best thing that I did next is to attach RoRo&#39;s combat pod image (See file taskbar.png in the
  repo) in the taskbar. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have not mentioned the wallpaper so far. I could go hardcore and draw my own, but I don&#39;t posess the right material
  for the task. I ended up going for an official art piece as my log in screen. &lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;There is one final thing that I wish I could do: Doing a paintjob on the laptop, but I don&#39;t think I have the
  dexterity for that. It would be cool to have it rocking a crimson.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
		<title>Mathematically get the brute-force upper bound number of turns needed to finish a turn-based RPG fight</title>
		<link>applethal.com//localhost:1313/sandbox/rpg/</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		
		<guid>//localhost:1313/sandbox/rpg/</guid>
		<description>
&lt;style&gt;
    .scrollable-div {
        overflow-x: auto;

        white-space: nowrap;

    }
&lt;/style&gt;

&lt;p&gt; I love turn based RPG games, especially those where I have no control over the mobility of my characters, as these
    reduce the problem size of my decisions, making me
    only decide on actions and ignore positioning. Other than that I get to enjoy the privilege of taking all the time I
    need in
    order to make a decision. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Weeks ago I was playing the original &lt;a href=&#34;https://de.wikipedia.org/wiki/Final_Fantasy_VII&#34;&gt;Final Fantasy VII&lt;/a&gt;
    for the first time in my life, and I somehow lost my patience
    against a group of monsters. Wanting to breeze
    through the game, I started to heuristically tinker ways in order to minimize the number of turns that it takes to
    end my fights as quick as I can. I had to account
    for my mana resource, especially since Final Fantasy VII&#39;s options in that regard were very costly back when I
    reached
    that chapter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wondered how speedrunners come up with the all those strategies that allow them to reach the high skies of the
    leaderboards; There is indeed potential for some Operational research! And that is what sparked the following idea:
    We can use linear programming to determine:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;The upper bound of the number of turns that it takes to finish a fight
    &lt;li&gt;Which attacks to use on which enemy
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I will be presenting here, sadly, does not work for every game out there, &lt;s&gt; it specifically works only for the
        aforementioned type of games with no
        press turn gimmicks (Sorry Shin Megami Tensei fans)&lt;/s&gt;. The model assumes that every member will move at the
    same turn. It is sadly an upper bound because these games usually come with
    RNG mechanics that may either be a hindrance, like evasion stats, or a blessing, like with critical hits. Other
    than that, the output of an attack may appear to be an integer, but in most games, the output stems from a ceiling
    function that considers many shenanigans, hence why some people may mention that their attacks could not reach a
    range.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;The model &lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Small disclaimer: This model will only work if you assume the following:
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;You have enough mana to finish the fight&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Your Party&#39;s HP is enough to tank through the fight&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;/ul&gt;




&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;With that out of the way, Let&#39;s discuss the input data. To model this, I need the following sets:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;\(c \in C\): Set of characters
    &lt;li&gt;\(e \in E\): Set of enemies
    &lt;li&gt;\(a,o,w \in A\): Set of attacks with \([a_1, a_2....a_n]\) \(\cup \) \([o_1,o_2....o_3]\)
        . \(a\) are the single
        target
        attacks, while \(o\) represent the attacks that can hit multiple enemies .
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for the parameters, the model requires:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;\(m_a\): The Mana/Stamina parameter of an attack \(a\)
    &lt;li&gt;\(HP_e\): The HP of an enemy \(e\)
    &lt;li&gt;\(p^c_{ae}\): The power coefficient of an attack \(a\) that the character \(c\) can apply to enemy \(e\)

&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The power of an attack is computed after considering the attack parameter of the character and adding up the enemy&#39;s
    weakness factor. This varies of course from game to game, consult the game&#39;s manual for the formulas, some games
    have this information public while some don&#39;t offer it and could use some years of reverse
    engineering. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With that out of the way, let&#39;s discuss how this is going to work. I decided to use a 3 index formulation, let
    \(X_{ca}^{e}\) be the variable that determines the number of attacks \(a\) a character \(c\) is using on an enemy
    \(e\), attacks that target multiple enemies will have a variable that contains only 2 indices, the attack \(a\) and
    the character \(c\).&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt; Finally, the following objective function aims to minimize the number of attack actions, since all characters move
    at the same turn. The output of the objective function will then be divided by the number of ally units that you
    control and that&#39;s how you get the upper bound of the turns needed to finish the fight. This objective function
    implicitly minimizes the number of turns if you think about it. With that out of the way, behold: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;scrollable-div&#34;&gt;
    \[min Z = \sum\limits_{a \in A}{} \sum\limits_{c\in C}{} \sum\limits_{e\in E}{} X^c_{ae} + \sum\limits_{o \in A}
    \sum\limits_{c\in C}{} {X^c_{o}}\]
    \[\sum\limits_{a \in A}{X^c_{ae} \cdot p^c_{ae} } + \sum\limits_{a \in A}{X^c_{o} \cdot p^c_{oe} \geq HP_e} \quad
    \forall e
    \in E \]
    \[
    \sum\limits_{a \in A} X^c_{ae} \cdot m_{a} + \sum\limits_{o \in A} X^c_{o} \cdot m_{o} \leq M_c \quad \forall c \in
    C
    \]


    \[X^c_{ae}, X^c_{o} \geq 0\]
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The objective function aims to minimize the number of attacks. The first constraint ensures that the chosen attacks
    will be sufficient to eliminate the enemies, while the second constraint allows the model to choose the attacks that
    can&#39;t outcredit the mana of each character. &lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;However, if you are playing &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Legend_of_Dragoon&#34;&gt;Legend of Dragoon&lt;/a&gt;
    (Great game by the way), this model works only in scenarios where you
    use a single character, since the game has an agility parameter that breaks linearity of turns.
    And for that, you might need an extra constraint for the item spells; since these have no mana costs but have
    limited usage
    depending on how many of them your inventory contains, which ensures that the item spells \(i\) used
    does not exceed their amounts, of course you might want to add the variable \(X^c_{i}\) to the first 2 constraints&#39;
    left
    hand side and express its positivity in the last constraint of course. You can, if you want, get rid of the \(c\)
    index
    since you are using only character but that won&#39;t change the size of the problem.&lt;/p&gt;

\[X^c_{i} \leq amount_i \quad \forall i \in I\]

&lt;p&gt;I have tried to see if I can include spells with cooldowns, which should use the following formulations, where
    \(w_{a}\): The cooldown coefficient of attack \(a\) :
    \[X_{ae}^c \cdot w_a \leq \sum\limits_{a&#39; \in A, a&#39; \neq a}{X_{a&#39;e}^c} \quad \forall a \in A\]
    \[X_{o}^c \cdot w_a \leq \sum\limits_{o&#39; \in A, o&#39; \neq o}{X_{o&#39;e}^c} \quad \forall a \in A\]

    The way these work is: If an attack variable with a cooldown goes active, then the model would use all the other
    attacks
    until their sum reaches the cooldown \(w_a\). Although this works, there might be scenarios where the model ends up
    over-killing the HP of an enemy. One way to fix this is to introduce a weight to each variable in the objective
    function with something like the ratio of the mana to the power of the attack \(\frac{\text{mana}}{\text{power}}\).
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the abilities that come with a cooldown coefficient cause your character(s) to be immobilized for \(w\) amount of
    turns (e.i. Attacks like Pokemon&#39;s hyper beam) instead of introducing a cooldown on the said attack, then the
    formula
    to get the number of turns transforms into this: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;scrollable-div&#34;&gt;
    \[
    \text{Turns} = \left\lceil \frac{\sum\limits_{a \in A}{} \sum\limits_{c\in C}{} \sum\limits_{e\in E}{} X^c_{ae}
    \cdot
    w_a + \sum\limits_{o \in A}
    \sum\limits_{c\in C}{} {X^c_{o} \cdot w_a}}{|C|} \right\rceil
    \]
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for the Shin Megami combat Tensei system, the number of turns can be estimated by exploiting the press system&#39;s
    rewarding
    gimmick, which gives an extra turn for every critical hit/elemental piercing attacks. Assuming of course that you
    have enough
    mana for all the spells, then the amount of turns necessary to end the fight is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;scrollable-div&#34;&gt;
    \[
    \text{Turns} = \left\lceil\frac{{Z - \text{effective spells}} }{|C|}\right\rceil 
    \]
&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;h2&gt;Closing words &lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As much as I enjoyed the making of this model, it&#39;s not perfect, and as mentioned before, it does not suit every game
    design. I Was thinking about adding more gimmicks considering damage over time (e.i. &lt;a
        href=&#34;https://bulbapedia.bulbagarden.net/wiki/Toxic_(move)&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Pokemon&#39;s toxic), but these had
    me consider using the big M constant, which would render my formulation weak if the wrong big M parameter is chosen.
    I might update this in the future. &lt;s&gt;Even though I mentioned that this would not work for the Megaten games with
        their
        press turn system, the output should give you an idea about how long the fight could go&lt;/s&gt;. Accounting for stat
    boosts
    mid-fights will turn it into a non-linear model, still, it does serve the job; I will passively see if there are any
    improvements that I can do to account for those special cases. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2&gt;Bonus: MMBN chips deck builder&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mega_Man_Battle_Network&#34;&gt;Mega man battle network (MMBN)&lt;/a&gt; is a series that I grew up with, a favourite to say the least.
It is a turn based JRPG made in the 00&#39;s that has some depth to its combat mechanics. I loved its character building aspect; the complexity of such challenges the
    creativity of the player, so much so that there are many who posted their builds online, and no build is perfect. Not only you have to decide on your deck, you 
    may also have to decide on what programs to install for your character, which adds lots of charm to its PVP. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Building decks follows a set of rules, the obvious being that you can&#39;t have more than 30 chips The rest of the constraints are game dependent (i.e. no 
    more than 5 mega chips in a folder...etc..). The best approach is to have a deck containing chips that can be chained with no interuptions, meaning 
    chips that can be picked together, hence why people recommend having a maximum of 3 different codes in a folder.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good builds usually come with a set of attacks that enable long combos. This is especially true since chaining combos is encouraged in the meta, as the more you immobilize 
    your opponents, the better!. The motivation behind 
writing this is to use linear programming as a tool to generate frame-efficient builds. Noting that the game runs at 60 fps, let this be the data input that we need:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;\(i \in I\): Set of chips
    &lt;li&gt;\(j \in J\): Set of chip codes
    &lt;li&gt;\(c \in C\): Set of chip categories (Standard, Mega, Giga)
        
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only parameters that I would require are the stun-lock numbers of each chip. These data can be extracted from the &lt;a href=https://wiki.n1gp.net/&gt;N1G wiki&lt;/a&gt;. Let \(f_i\) be the stun-lock frame 
parameter of a chip \(i\). For this entire setup I require two decision variables: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;\(x_{i,j,c}\): Positive variable that decides upon choosing chip \(i\) with the code \(j\) from the category \(c\)
    &lt;li&gt;\(y_j\): Positive variable that decides if the code \(j\) is chosen
    
        
&lt;/ul&gt;
\[\max Z = \sum\limits_{i\in I}{}\sum\limits_{j\in J}{} \sum\limits_{c \in C}{x_{i,j,c} \cdot f_i} \]

\[\sum\limits_{i\in I}{}\sum\limits_{j\in J}{} \sum\limits_{c \in C}{x_{i,j,c}} = 20\]

\[x_{i,j,c} \leq y_j \quad \forall i \in I, j \in J\]

\[\sum\limits_{j \in J / \{*\} }{y_j} \leq 2 \]

\[\sum\limits_{j \in J}{x_{i,j,c}} \leq 3 \quad \forall i \in I\]

\[\sum\limits_{MEGA \in C}{x_{i,j,MEGA}} \leq 5 \]

\[\sum\limits_{GIGA \in C}{x_{i,j,GIGA}} \leq 1 \]

&lt;p&gt; The objective function Z aims to maximize the stun lock potential of the deck. The first constraint prevents the program from picking more than 20 chips. You can set it to however you want, 
I usually leave 10 cards for defensive options, which are not considered here in the formulation. The next 2 constraints limit the amount of chip codes that you may have, feel free to adjust it to 
any number other than 2, I prefer having no more than 2 codes, asterisk codes are excluded from the constraint because they can be mixed with any code. Afterwards you&#39;ve got game specific constraints, as
of the latest 3 games in the series, I believe you can&#39;t have more than 3, 5 and 1 standard, mega and giga chips respectively (Unless you edit your character build with some NCP that enable more). Damage isn&#39;t everything! One 
    con of this model is that it won&#39;t contain program advance combos due to the technicalities of the said combos, another issue is the fact that the average PvP person has the super armor NCP installed, which renders this entire 
    model useless.
&lt;/p&gt;




</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
		<title>Wraps with hacked meat</title>
		<link>applethal.com//localhost:1313/recommendations/recipes/wraps_hacked_meat/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		
		<guid>//localhost:1313/recommendations/recipes/wraps_hacked_meat/</guid>
		<description>


I was just roaming online until I hit a video that claims that the recipe is quick so I gave it a go!

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Cook the meat in a pan for aprox. 20 minutes @8/10 temp
  &lt;li&gt; Add some cheese to the meat in the pan and keep mixing it
  &lt;li&gt; Cut the tomatoes and onions
  &lt;li&gt; Stuff everything in a wrap
  &lt;li&gt; Use the oven to do some final cooking for no more than 6 minutes

&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
I can&#39;t name anyone who dislikes fast food. As ignorant as I may be, I always pictured the difficulty of crafting sandwishes as something that resides outside the scope of my dexterity. One day I was roaming Instagram and somehow stumbled across someone uploading a video tutoring the recipe. I was attracted by the fact that the uploader mentioned the words &#34;It&#39;s easy and anyone can do it&#34;, so I gave it a try. &lt;br&gt; I was going to upload this recipe few months ago, but I was not ready to share it online since I had some discomfort with respect to my cooking skills. When I first saw the recipe online, the chef strictly stated to use the oven for no more than 6 minutes. I was punished multiple times for breaking this rule, heck, cooking it for yet another minute on top was not a rewarding behaviour &lt;br&gt;Not only it contains lots of protein, but its budget is super friendly, half a kilo of the meat can be used to make 4 wraps. I have seen some people directly stuffing the cheese together with everything instead of cooking it together with the meat, argumenting that the cheese melts by the time the oven does its job. I honestly can&#39;t tell
if the final product is any different, as the taste of the meat and the sauce dominates the wrap, making it hard for me to notice. The only thing that I would like to touch upon, is the fact that mixing the cheese in the pan makes cleaning the latter much more time consuming.&lt;/p&gt;


</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
		<title>Systematically visualize the impact of linear constraints in a MIP</title>
		<link>applethal.com//localhost:1313/sandbox/constraints/</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		
		<guid>//localhost:1313/sandbox/constraints/</guid>
		<description>&lt;link rel=&#34;stylesheet&#34; type=&#34;text/css&#34; href=&#34;https://tikzjax.com/v1/fonts.css&#34;&gt;
&lt;script src=&#34;https://tikzjax.com/v1/tikzjax.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mixed integer linear programming (MIP) is easy to comprehend on the surface, you just plug in
    a linear constraint and voilà! You now have transformed an LP into a MIP. Learning how to
    systematically write a model with its constraints and component is, sadly, a matter
    of training. Watching all these professors and these seniors formulate constraints at ease makes
    it look easy, which may or may not evoke an air of imposter syndrome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The goal is to shape the perspective around the world of linear optimization, that&#39;s the passive
    effect of doing exercises. Some of these constraints seem intuitive but once you get into the deeper
    side of linear programming (I.E. Big M, logical constraints...etc), it becomes a bit hard to visualize the effect
    of a constraint with respect to the optimization problem that you are facing. If you are a beginner in operational
    research and having skipped mathematics, chances are, that every time these
    constraints are brought up, you might feel as if you are missing something elementary. It becomes much more
    frustrating if you try to research any specific since you can&#39;t tell where to start, as the anything revolving the
    constraint

    is not so centralized and accessible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Shape your perception&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This article is aimed at introducing the method that I use to understand any linear constraint.
    This method is sadly not directly communicated, as it is to be concluded through intuition and can not be
    easily googled. The average Operational research guide or blog expects the person to have some mathematical
    reflexes. This method is meant to be fool-proof, I believe that no one may face difficulties with it.
    This article serves also as a way to centralize most of the modelling tricks that I have learned, you may
    use it as a reference to come back to later on.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Unless relaxed, binary variables express the execution of a decision; if the variable equals 1,
    the decision to execute what the variable expresses is enabled. Do you produce X, do you use X, do you allocate
    X...etc...
&lt;/p&gt;


\[
x=\begin{cases}
1 &amp; \text{Decision is to be executed}\\
0 &amp; \text{Otherwise}
\end{cases}
\]


&lt;p&gt;When writing mathematical models, it is imperative to express linear functions (hence the term Linear in the model&#39;s
    property). Many modelling
    tricks were invented to cope with constraints that can not be directly translated from a verbal statement. Allow me
    to present the following modelling
    trick: &lt;/p&gt;


\[
x \leq y

\]


\[

x, y \in \{0,1\}
\]




&lt;p&gt;This trick helps to formulate situations where the execution of a variable (in this case \(x\)) forces another
    variable (\(y\)) to be true, though we don&#39;t
    care about the latter, we want to force them both to be enabled if the former gets the value of 1. In other words:
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; If x = 1 then y = 1
    &lt;li&gt; If x = 0 then we don&#39;t care if y = 1 or 0
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Concrete example: &lt;/u&gt;If Product X is produced, I want Product Y to be produced alongside it. However, I still
    want
    the option to decide on producing Product Y independently of whether Product X gets produced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How could I understand the desired outcome of this expression ? Before presenting the method, let me explain how this
    whole thing works: &lt;br&gt;

    Graphically, this is how the constraint looks like. Any point that exists outside the area is invalid/infeasible.
    The role of the constraint is to make sure that only the integer points within this area are chosen. With that said,
    the point (1,0) as seen in the picture below is infeasible, &lt;u&gt;&lt;b&gt;as the value 1 can never be lower or equal to
            0&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/u&gt;.


&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&#34;scroll-container&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;tikzs&#34;&gt;
        &lt;script type=&#34;text/tikz&#34;&gt;
            \begin{tikzpicture}[scale=4]

    \draw[-&gt;] (-0.5,0) -- (2.5,0) node[right] {$x$};
    \draw[-&gt;] (0,-0.5) -- (0,2.5) node[above] {$y$};


    \draw[step=1, gray, very thin] (0,0) grid (2.5, 2.5);


    \fill[black] (0,0) circle (1pt) node[below left] {$(0,0)$};
    \fill[black] (1,1) circle (1pt) node[above right] {$(1,1)$};
    \fill[black] (0,1) circle (1pt) node[above left] {$(0,1)$};
    \fill[black] (1,0) circle (1pt) node[above left] {$(1,0)$};


    \begin{scope}[fill=gray, fill opacity=0.3]
        \clip (0,0) -- (1,1) -- (0,1) -- cycle;
        \fill[gray, opacity=0.3] (0,0) rectangle (1,1);
    \end{scope}


    \foreach \x in {0,1,2} {
        \draw (\x,1pt) -- (\x,-1pt) node[below] {$\x$};
    }
    \foreach \y in {0,1,2} {
        \draw (1pt,\y) -- (-1pt,\y) node[left] {$\y$};
    }

\end{tikzpicture}
      &lt;/script&gt;

    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;p style=&#34;color: #888; font-size: 14px; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;Graphical depiction of the aforementioned constraint
    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;That&#39;s right, by all logic, 1 can&#39;t be lower or equal than 0 for sure, so how do I perceive this ? Truth is, I don&#39;t
    draw a 2 dimensional axis and a feasible region ? There is an even faster way:


&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div style=&#34;display: flex; justify-content: center; align-items: center;&#34;&gt;
    &lt;table border=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;border-collapse: collapse; text-align: center; width: 60%;&#34;&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;th style=&#34;width: 20%;&#34;&gt;X&lt;/th&gt;
            &lt;th style=&#34;width: 20%;&#34;&gt;Y&lt;/th&gt;
            &lt;th&gt;Feasible ?&lt;/th&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;Feasible&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;Infeasible&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;Feasible&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;Feasible&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Here is how I do it: I draw a table up to \(n\) number of variables on the columns, and then I list
    all of their possible values, luckily, what makes this method faster than graphically checks is the fact that the
    variables are binary and can&#39;t have anything other
    than 0s and 1s, which by extension means that you will have \(2^n\) rows. Finally, I check the feasibility with
    respect to the mechanics of the constraint.
    This is a method that I absorbed by watching a student do it few years ago, and as I mentioned, I have not seen this
    in any OR literature yet.
&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Although this method is meant to quickly help understand how a mathematical constraint works, I have seen that
    same student use it to write and design constraints. I believe this could help in this regard, especially if the
    variables are strictly binary. I would be happy to see if there is a better and quicker way, I will certainly update
    this guide
    if I ever find anything fruitful.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have to admit that I still relay on my muscle memory to write optimization models, it takes some intelligence
    to write some cool constraints. It&#39;s an art!
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Modeling If → NOT&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&#39;ve seen the logical IF → Then true, the following becomes easier to understand after utilizing the method:&lt;/p&gt;


\[
x \leq 1 - y
\]

\[
x, y \in \{0,1\}
\]

&lt;div style=&#34;display: flex; justify-content: center; align-items: center;&#34;&gt;
    &lt;table border=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;border-collapse: collapse; text-align: center; width: 60%;&#34;&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;th style=&#34;width: 20%;&#34;&gt;X&lt;/th&gt;
            &lt;th style=&#34;width: 20%;&#34;&gt;Y&lt;/th&gt;
            &lt;th&gt;Feasible ?&lt;/th&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;Feasible&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;Feasible&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;Feasible&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;Infeasible&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Notice that \(x\) and \(y\) can never both contain a value of 1 at the same time, the constraint is feasible only
    when either \(x\) or \(y\) gets the value of 1 (or 0 optionally). Verbally, this expression says the following: If
    \(x\) gets 1 then \(y\) should NOT get 1 and vice versa.
    I believe this equation can be visually simplified by swapping its terms like this; this is how I remember it:&lt;/p&gt;

\[
x + y \leq 1
\]

&lt;p&gt;Like this, you may easily remember it by considering that 2 can never be greater than 1. Next, I will display
    how to model the AND statement.
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;h2&gt;Modeling AND&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Picture this: What if I want to either produce both \(x\) and \(y\) at the same time or produce neither. I can&#39;t
    simply plug+in the last inequality from the previous section because there would always be the off chance that
    either
    \(x\) or \(y\) get a value of 1. Let&#39;s review the nature of the desirable output, either:

&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Neither \(x\) or \(y\) may be produced&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;We produce \(x\) and \(y\) at the same time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One idea that I would use as a headstart is to use the following equation: \(x + y = 2\), but the issue with this one
    is that
    it does not allow the first part of the condition to function, as it will always result into producing both
    products. One workaround to deal with this is to introduce a new binary variable \(z\) that goes enabled &lt;b&gt;&lt;u&gt;only
            if&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/b&gt;
    \(x\) and \(y\)
    have a value of 1.

&lt;/p&gt;

\[z \leq x\]
\[z \leq y\]
\[x + y - 1 \leq z \]
\[x,y,z \in \{0,1\}\]


&lt;p&gt;With this combination, only the two desired outcomes may happen. All of these constraints are essential. The third
    inequality
    is the very key component of the whole logic. As far as logic is concerned, with the boolean checks table in mind,
    for each variable, we check the feasibility not for just one constraint, but for them all:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;display: flex; justify-content: center; align-items: center;&#34;&gt;
    &lt;table border=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;border-collapse: collapse; text-align: center; width: 60%;&#34;&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;th style=&#34;width: 20%;&#34;&gt;X&lt;/th&gt;
            &lt;th style=&#34;width: 20%;&#34;&gt;Y&lt;/th&gt;
            &lt;th style=&#34;width: 20%;&#34;&gt;Z&lt;/th&gt;
            &lt;th&gt;Feasible ?&lt;/th&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;Feasible&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;Infeasible&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;Infeasible&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;Infeasible&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;Infeasible&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;Infeasible&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;Infeasible&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;Feasible&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;

    &lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;




&lt;h2&gt;Modelling precedence constraints&lt;/h2&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Precedence constraints usually concern problems where sequencing is a hard constraint that must occur, else the
    modeled
    problem may be infeasible.
    This is usually the case for complex problems like Vehicle routing problems (VRP), Traveling salesman problem (TSP)
    and scheduling where choosing the right
    permutations is crucial to controlling the objective function.

    &lt;br&gt; Naturally, when designing constraints for such problems, in VRPs for instance, you might be challenged by a
    capacity constraint, forcing you to choose the
    right sequence of customers such as to respect your limited capacity. In Flow/Job shop scheduling, you would want a
    sequence of jobs such as they don&#39;t overlap on each other
    and between each machine. Let&#39;s use the former as a use case!
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In MIP, sequencing is often modeled with a decision variable that denotes if we execute action \(i\) before \(j\), do
    we visit customer \(i\) before \(j\),
    do we execute job \(i\) before \(j\)... A single index is not enough to tell a permutation (As of today, who knows
    if
    someone invents something crazy).&lt;/p&gt;



\[
x_{i,j}=\begin{cases}
1 &amp; \text{Execute action \(i\) before action \(j\)}\\
0 &amp; \text{Otherwise}
\end{cases}
\]



&lt;p&gt;In a TSP environment, you would want to have a Hamiltonian cycle across all the nodes. With that variable in mind,
    one way to achieve this is to introduce
    a constraint that expresses the following: we will leave each node once. If applied as intended, you should have a
    graph where &lt;b&gt;&lt;u&gt;each node has 1 successor and 1 predecessor.&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/b&gt; since we
    will enter a node and leaving it; in other words: Make sure we use the paths between each node only once:&lt;/p&gt;

\[
\sum\limits_{i \in V \setminus \{j\}}{x_{ij} = 1} \quad \forall i \in V
\]

\[
\sum\limits_{j \in V \setminus \{i\}}{x_{ij} = 1} \quad \forall j \in V
\]

&lt;p&gt;This would be the best time to talk a bit in-depth about the syntax of these constraints. You see, because of
    how generic these problems are, in academics, these equations are written with the above algebraic syntax to
    optimize readability. Using the table would have
    you decompose the constraint first. I usually start with the space domain first, we have a for statement here that
    defines
    the amount of constraints that we have to account for, in this case it would be for every \(i\) node in the graph,
    next
    we have a sum statement here that simply chains every variable. We will sum over all the paths that are connected to
    the node \(i\),
    the node \(i\) is excluded because that would bring up a variable that decides on a path that goes from the node
    \(i\) and leads back to it.

    As you can see, the key here is to always comprehend
    the syntax to decompose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let \(V\) be the set of nodes, the above constraints verbally say: For each pair of nodes, only one path would be
    chosen. This constraint is forced for every \(i\) and \(j\) couple. The objective function takes
    care of the optimization part in which it chooses the set of connections following the logic of the 2 constraints.
    For each node \(i\) and for each node \(j\) you will have \(V - 1\) constraints to check. In the following table
    I will present how the feasibility check looks like for every \(j\)th node in the graph. Note that the TSP assumes
    graph symmetry, going from 1 to 2 is the same as going from 2 to 1 \(x_{12} = x_{21} \), so if the program ever
    enables one of these paths, it implicitly enables it from the other sides.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;scroll-container&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div style=&#34;display: flex; justify-content: center; align-items: center;&#34;&gt;
        &lt;table border=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;border-collapse: collapse; text-align: center; width: 80%;&#34;&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
                &lt;th style=&#34;width: 33%;&#34;&gt;Constraint 1: \( x_{12} + x_{13} = 1 \)&lt;/th&gt;
                &lt;th style=&#34;width: 33%;&#34;&gt;Constraint 2: \( x_{21} + x_{23} = 1 \)&lt;/th&gt;
                &lt;th style=&#34;width: 33%;&#34;&gt;Constraint 3: \( x_{31} + x_{32} = 1 \)&lt;/th&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;
                    &lt;table border=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;border-collapse: collapse; text-align: center; width: 100%;&#34;&gt;
                        &lt;tr&gt;
                            &lt;th&gt;\( x_{12} \)&lt;/th&gt;
                            &lt;th&gt;\( x_{13} \)&lt;/th&gt;
                            &lt;th&gt;Feasible?&lt;/th&gt;
                        &lt;/tr&gt;
                        &lt;tr&gt;
                            &lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
                            &lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
                            &lt;td&gt;Infeasible&lt;/td&gt;
                        &lt;/tr&gt;
                        &lt;tr&gt;
                            &lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
                            &lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
                            &lt;td&gt;Feasible&lt;/td&gt;
                        &lt;/tr&gt;
                        &lt;tr&gt;
                            &lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
                            &lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
                            &lt;td&gt;Feasible&lt;/td&gt;
                        &lt;/tr&gt;
                        &lt;tr&gt;
                            &lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
                            &lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
                            &lt;td&gt;Infeasible&lt;/td&gt;
                        &lt;/tr&gt;
                    &lt;/table&gt;
                &lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;
                    &lt;table border=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;border-collapse: collapse; text-align: center; width: 100%;&#34;&gt;
                        &lt;tr&gt;
                            &lt;th&gt;\( x_{21} \)&lt;/th&gt;
                            &lt;th&gt;\( x_{23} \)&lt;/th&gt;
                            &lt;th&gt;Feasible?&lt;/th&gt;
                        &lt;/tr&gt;
                        &lt;tr&gt;
                            &lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
                            &lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
                            &lt;td&gt;Infeasible&lt;/td&gt;
                        &lt;/tr&gt;
                        &lt;tr&gt;
                            &lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
                            &lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
                            &lt;td&gt;Feasible&lt;/td&gt;
                        &lt;/tr&gt;
                        &lt;tr&gt;
                            &lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
                            &lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
                            &lt;td&gt;Feasible&lt;/td&gt;
                        &lt;/tr&gt;
                        &lt;tr&gt;
                            &lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
                            &lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
                            &lt;td&gt;Infeasible&lt;/td&gt;
                        &lt;/tr&gt;
                    &lt;/table&gt;
                &lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;
                    &lt;table border=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;border-collapse: collapse; text-align: center; width: 100%;&#34;&gt;
                        &lt;tr&gt;
                            &lt;th&gt;\( x_{31} \)&lt;/th&gt;
                            &lt;th&gt;\( x_{32} \)&lt;/th&gt;
                            &lt;th&gt;Feasible?&lt;/th&gt;
                        &lt;/tr&gt;
                        &lt;tr&gt;
                            &lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
                            &lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
                            &lt;td&gt;Infeasible&lt;/td&gt;
                        &lt;/tr&gt;
                        &lt;tr&gt;
                            &lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
                            &lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
                            &lt;td&gt;Feasible&lt;/td&gt;
                        &lt;/tr&gt;
                        &lt;tr&gt;
                            &lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
                            &lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
                            &lt;td&gt;Feasible&lt;/td&gt;
                        &lt;/tr&gt;
                        &lt;tr&gt;
                            &lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
                            &lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
                            &lt;td&gt;Infeasible&lt;/td&gt;
                        &lt;/tr&gt;
                    &lt;/table&gt;
                &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;/table&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;


&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;scroll-container&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div style=&#34;display: flex; justify-content: center; align-items: center;&#34;&gt;
        &lt;table border=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;border-collapse: collapse; text-align: center; width: 60%;&#34;&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
                &lt;th style=&#34;width: 33%;&#34;&gt;Constraint 1: \( x_{21} + x_{31} = 1 \)&lt;/th&gt;
                &lt;th style=&#34;width: 33%;&#34;&gt;Constraint 2: \( x_{12} + x_{32} = 1 \)&lt;/th&gt;
                &lt;th style=&#34;width: 33%;&#34;&gt;Constraint 3: \( x_{13} + x_{23} = 1 \)&lt;/th&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;
                    &lt;table border=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;border-collapse: collapse; text-align: center; width: 100%;&#34;&gt;
                        &lt;tr&gt;
                            &lt;th&gt;\( x_{21} \)&lt;/th&gt;
                            &lt;th&gt;\( x_{31} \)&lt;/th&gt;
                            &lt;th&gt;Feasible?&lt;/th&gt;
                        &lt;/tr&gt;
                        &lt;tr&gt;
                            &lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
                            &lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
                            &lt;td&gt;Infeasible&lt;/td&gt;
                        &lt;/tr&gt;
                        &lt;tr&gt;
                            &lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
                            &lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
                            &lt;td&gt;Feasible&lt;/td&gt;
                        &lt;/tr&gt;
                        &lt;tr&gt;
                            &lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
                            &lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
                            &lt;td&gt;Feasible&lt;/td&gt;
                        &lt;/tr&gt;
                        &lt;tr&gt;
                            &lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
                            &lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
                            &lt;td&gt;Infeasible&lt;/td&gt;
                        &lt;/tr&gt;
                    &lt;/table&gt;
                &lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;
                    &lt;table border=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;border-collapse: collapse; text-align: center; width: 100%;&#34;&gt;
                        &lt;tr&gt;
                            &lt;th&gt;\( x_{12} \)&lt;/th&gt;
                            &lt;th&gt;\( x_{32} \)&lt;/th&gt;
                            &lt;th&gt;Feasible?&lt;/th&gt;
                        &lt;/tr&gt;
                        &lt;tr&gt;
                            &lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
                            &lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
                            &lt;td&gt;Infeasible&lt;/td&gt;
                        &lt;/tr&gt;
                        &lt;tr&gt;
                            &lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
                            &lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
                            &lt;td&gt;Feasible&lt;/td&gt;
                        &lt;/tr&gt;
                        &lt;tr&gt;
                            &lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
                            &lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
                            &lt;td&gt;Feasible&lt;/td&gt;
                        &lt;/tr&gt;
                        &lt;tr&gt;
                            &lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
                            &lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
                            &lt;td&gt;Infeasible&lt;/td&gt;
                        &lt;/tr&gt;
                    &lt;/table&gt;
                &lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;
                    &lt;table border=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;border-collapse: collapse; text-align: center; width: 100%;&#34;&gt;
                        &lt;tr&gt;
                            &lt;th&gt;\( x_{13} \)&lt;/th&gt;
                            &lt;th&gt;\( x_{23} \)&lt;/th&gt;
                            &lt;th&gt;Feasible?&lt;/th&gt;
                        &lt;/tr&gt;
                        &lt;tr&gt;
                            &lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
                            &lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
                            &lt;td&gt;Infeasible&lt;/td&gt;
                        &lt;/tr&gt;
                        &lt;tr&gt;
                            &lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
                            &lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
                            &lt;td&gt;Feasible&lt;/td&gt;
                        &lt;/tr&gt;
                        &lt;tr&gt;
                            &lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
                            &lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
                            &lt;td&gt;Feasible&lt;/td&gt;
                        &lt;/tr&gt;
                        &lt;tr&gt;
                            &lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
                            &lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
                            &lt;td&gt;Infeasible&lt;/td&gt;
                        &lt;/tr&gt;
                    &lt;/table&gt;
                &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;/table&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since we have a set of 3 nodes, you would expect your TSP solution to have exactly \(V\) number of arcs, so without
    even thinking about it, feasible are the inequalities that enable no more and no less than 3 edges over all the
    nodes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As said earlier, with respect to the above constraints, the objective function will choose the edges that ensure the
    tour with the minimal costs. Funnily enough, these constraints are sufficient for a case where the graph contains 3
    to 4 nodes, as no combination of edges
    can make an infeasible TSP solution, until you introduce a 5 nodes graph....&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;div class=&#34;scroll-container&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;tikzs&#34;&gt;
        &lt;script type=&#34;text/tikz&#34;&gt;
            \begin{tikzpicture}

\node[shape=circle,draw=black] (A) at (0,6) {$1$};
\node[shape=circle,draw=black] (B) at (0,3) {$2$};
\node[shape=circle,draw=black] (C) at (0,5) {$3$};
\node[shape=circle,draw=black] (D) at (2,5) {$4$};
\node[shape=circle,draw=black] (E) at (4,5) {$5$};

\path (A) edge (C);
\path (C) edge (B);
\path (D) edge (E);
\path (A) edge (C);

\end{tikzpicture}
      &lt;/script&gt;

    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;p style=&#34;color: #888; font-size: 14px; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;Nu uh! This is not a Hamiltonian tour!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;So if you have noticed, we told the MIP to look for the cheapest connections, and so it executed what we told it.
    Sadly it does not come in
    terms with the desired output. If you think about it, and if we hard check all the edges, all the constraints are
    feasible. The issue lies
    then in the logic of the constraints then.&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;p&gt;One idea to deal with this is to weight each node with an index to indicate its position in the permutation. In a
    TSP, the starting node
    matters not since we are going to visit it anyways. Using a continuous variable \(u_{i}\), each node will be
    assigned
    an index, we would
    then want to implement a logic that says the following: If we use the path \(x_{i,j}\), the index of the \(j\)
    should be higher than \(i\)&#39;s index.&lt;/p&gt;

\[
x_{i,j} \Rightarrow u_{i} - u_{j} = 1
\]

\[
u_{1} = 1
\]


\[
2 \leq u_{i} \leq n
\]

&lt;p&gt;So far so good, but then, how do you link these 2 constraints together ? Getting deeper in operational research would
    eventually expose you to a famous constraint that helps against
    permutation-based problems. The Miller-Tucker-Zemling (Miller et al., 1960)
    can be seen in various MIPs, it uses continuous variables to magically eliminate subtours and ensure correct
    permuting.
&lt;p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As of my limited knowledge, the non-linearity of the constraint lies within that if statement and that&#39;s how the MTZ
    constraint comes into play.
    Using a big constant \(M\) (ideally equal to the number of nodes) together with the \(x_{i,j}\) variable one can
    combine these constraints
    into one:&lt;/p&gt;

\[
u_i - u_j + 1 \leq n(x_{i,j}-1)
\]


&lt;p&gt;If \(x_{i,j}\) is 1, it cancels itself together with the constant and the inequality turns into \(u_{j} \geq
    u_{i} + 1
    \), because \(u_{i}\) ranges between 2 and \(n\), and together with the other constraints, the final solution would
    be
    a graph containing no subtours. Let&#39;s take a look at how this would look like by the time we reach the 3rd
    iteration:&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&#34;scroll-container&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;tikzs&#34;&gt;
        &lt;script type=&#34;text/tikz&#34;&gt;
            \begin{tikzpicture}

\node[shape=circle,draw=black] (A) at (0,6) {$1$};
\node[shape=circle,draw=black] (B) at (0,3) {$2$};
\node[shape=circle,draw=black] (C) at (0,5) {$3$};
\node[shape=circle,draw=black] (D) at (2,5) {$4$};
\node[shape=circle,draw=black] (E) at (4,5) {$5$};

\path (A) edge (C);
\path (C) edge (B);



\end{tikzpicture}
      &lt;/script&gt;

    &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Let&#39;s pretend that \(x_{2,4} = 1\), this turns the inequality into \(u_{4} \geq u_{2} + 1\), as of reaching node
    \(2\), the algorithm decided that \(u_{2} = 3\):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;scroll-container&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div style=&#34;display: flex; justify-content: center; align-items: center;&#34;&gt;
        &lt;table border=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;border-collapse: collapse; text-align: center; width: 60%;&#34;&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
                &lt;th style=&#34;width: 20%;&#34;&gt;\(u_{2} + 1\)&lt;/th&gt;
                &lt;th style=&#34;width: 20%;&#34;&gt;\(u_{4}\)&lt;/th&gt;
                &lt;th&gt;Feasible ?&lt;/th&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;Infeasible&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;Infeasible&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;Feasible&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;Feasible&lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;/table&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The solver has no choice but to either assign either 4 or 5, and because of the subsequent node after taking that
    path, it ends up ultimatly choosing the value \(u_j = 4\). If for whatever reason the said path gets a 0, then the
    big constant \(n\) will outweight every possible choice, neglating the connection between the nodes, as no
    value for the two variables \(u_i\) and \(u_j\) can ensure feasibility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For VRP and Scheduling problems, enumeration is not necessary as these problems already come with continuous
    variables that can be intelligently used as an
    engine for the inequalities.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2&gt;Don&#39;t constraint yourself! Be creative!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One constraint setup that I saw years ago happened to be a fancy answer to the following question, which comes from a
    test
    that I had to pass:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;i&gt; &#34;Now assume that if product 8 is produced, products 7 and 11 cannot be produced.
        Give
        the required linear constraint(s) on the variables \(Y_p\)! (2 points)&#34;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using some muscle memory, you may use the following constraints that help achieve what the question demands:&lt;/p&gt;

\[Y_8 + Y_7 \leq 1\]
\[Y_8 + Y_7 \leq 1\]

&lt;p&gt;Both of these constraints are correct, but there is an even fancier way; a formulation that I found so elegant that lives in my head rent free:
&lt;/p&gt;

\[Y_8 + \frac{1}{2} (Y_7 + Y_{11}) \leq 1\]

&lt;p&gt;Every time I tutor people in quantitative methods, the name of the said subject that contains that question. I always
    bring this up inequality up. The way it is written makes me often want to toy around with the arithmetics, doing my
    best to
    optimize the number of constraints that I have to formulate. My point is: Don&#39;t restrict yourself with all of those
    tricks,
    try every playing with the formulas, see what you can achieve and unlock!
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;h2&gt;Reference &lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Miller, C.E., Tucker, A.W. and Zemlin, R.A. (1960) &lt;i&gt;Integer Programming Formulations and Traveling Salesman
        Problems. Journal of the Association for Computing Machinery, 7, 326-329 &lt;/i&gt;.
    https://doi.org/10.1145/321043.321046 &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
		<title>Divided by zero - Living in a stochastic environment</title>
		<link>applethal.com//localhost:1313/blog/divided_by_zero_2/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		
		<guid>//localhost:1313/blog/divided_by_zero_2/</guid>
		<description>&lt;style&gt;
    a {
        text-decoration: none;
        color: yellow;
    }

    .scrollable-div {
        overflow-x: auto;
        white-space: nowrap;
    }

    .tikzs {
        text-align: center;
        background-color: white;
        width: fit-content;
        margin: auto;
        padding: 20px;
        border-radius: 8px;
        overflow-x: auto;

    }

    .tikzs svg {
        overflow: visible !important;

    }

    .scroll-container {
        overflow-x: auto;
        width: 100%;
        max-width: 100%;
    }

    h3 {
        text-decoration: underline;
    }
&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;script src=&#34;https://tikzjax.com/v1/tikzjax.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Operant_conditioning_chamber&#34;&gt;The skinner box&lt;/a&gt; is a psychology experiment
    that further
    explores operant conditioning. Simply put: Behave well and you will get rewarded, choose the wrong option and you
    will
    get punished.
    Be it humans or animals, any entity would always seek to maximize its utility function. Honestly I wish this analogy
    was used
    in the artificial intelligence resources that I used. This goes true on the surface, though you might
    realize that ultimately everything goes back to &lt;a
        href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Maslow%27s_hierarchy_of_needs&#34;&gt;Maslow&#39;s pyramid of needs&lt;/a&gt;, which adds
    even
    more depth to the complexity of what makes a human being.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we grow up, we shape our knowledge base and keep learning to enhance our future interactions through the
    experiences we gain.
    Part of the learning process is to make mistakes (Or watch people do mistakes), since they lead to nothing but
    punishment, as rewards feel
    cheap in comparison to the pain attached to choosing the wrong dialogue option.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As far as interactions go, I like to picture them as branch and bound models, where each root node has up to N
    options. If you overthink much, chances are, you tree will be transformed in a non-tree graph where some decisions
    might lead to a loop. Having trees with a high number of options might lead to decision fatigue, extending all the
    way
    to decision avoidance A.K.A. I ain&#39;t doing that. Having anxiety may also lead to the latter in a way that hinders
    your
    calculations, heck it might
    even introduce some negative weights to the reward associated to the option that is, in practise, the most rewarding
    one. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each node in the graph denotes the state of the situation, whereas the edges represent the decisions. Each state has
    an objective function that is to be maximized,
    or minimized; this function can quantify anything (Ex: Patience, love, strength, energy...etc..), it all comes down
    to
    your imagination.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&#34;scroll-container&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;tikzs&#34;&gt;
        &lt;g transform&gt;
            &lt;script type=&#34;text/tikz&#34;&gt;
            \begin{tikzpicture}[
scale = 1.5, transform shape, thick,
tree node/.style = {align=center, inner sep=0pt, text centered, font =
\scriptsize},
S/.style = {draw, circle, minimum size = 8mm},
grow = down,
level 1/.style = {sibling distance=3cm},
level 2/.style = {sibling distance=4cm},
level 3/.style = {sibling distance=5cm},
level distance = 1.25cm]

\node [S, label=above:{$Z = 0$}] {$1$}
    child{node [S,label=left:{$Z = 0$}] {$2$}
        edge from parent node[above left, font = \scriptsize] {avoid}}
    child{node [S, label=above right:{$Z = 5$}] {$3$}
        child {node [S, label=left:{$Z = 15$}] {$4$}
            child {node [S, label=left:{$Z = 0$}] {$6$}
                edge from parent node[above left, font = \scriptsize] {low ball}}
            child {node [S, label=left:{$Z = 20$}] {$7$}
                edge from parent node[above right, font = \scriptsize] {pay}}
                edge from parent node[above left, font = \scriptsize] {refuse}
        }
        child {node [S, label=right:{$Z = 10$}] {$5$}
                edge from parent node[above right, font = \scriptsize] {accept}
        }
        edge from parent node[above right, font = \scriptsize] {talk}};



\end{tikzpicture}
          &lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:center; color:grey; font-size:small;&#34;&gt;Negotiating a trade, yes I usually give up easily, hence why
    my tree&#39;s depth is short.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone loves smooth and swift communications, navigating decision trees is a daunting task, it prompts me often to
    rely on muscle memory and instinct, something which I usually train by creating simulations in my head, hoping that
    their interactions will be 1:1 with what I picture. I often envy those who
    can quickly sort themselves out with little to no effort. One way to heuristically deal with this is to reduce the
    amount of
    options
    that you
    have to deal with, each experience that you gain acts as a cache in your memory, allowing you to reduce the length
    of
    the tree by
    seeing patterns in your daily life, though at some points it might introduce new complexities depending on the
    topic. Paradoxically enough, with experience, you end up learning new branching paths
    and
    new
    options to choose from. Skilled manipulators tend to have intelligently designed trees; psychopaths however tend to
    have multiple trees instead, one
    for each profile.

&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After all, I find it crucial for every human to learn and gain as experience as they can. I observed that the
    punishment
    factor of taking the bad options tend to be lighter the younger a human is; as you grow, people would often presume
    that
    you are capable of measuring and designing good decision trees. It&#39;s an important skill that some people make money
    off of nowadays, most departments have an advisory bureau, ready to enrich your trees with all the solutions you can
    afford. This is important as life is filled with many surprises that you can&#39;t really quantify. It is expected of an
    adult to be ready for the
    many possibilities that they may encounter. If at any time frame my actions contradict the knowledge base of any other party,
    the first assumption that I receive questions the cultural gap between us; some may even call me insane.
    &lt;br&gt;
    I don&#39;t possess the skills nor do I qualify to say the following statement, but I believe communicating has a huge
    search space that I would deem it \(NP-hard\) if that&#39;s what it takes. With everything discussed so far, I would
    require a mix of emotions and intelligence from my end in order to achieve my goals, both of which can be trained
    by engaging with society.
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Having a streak of unsuccessful deals can lead to phenomenon called &lt;a
        href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Loss_aversion&#34;&gt;loss aversion&lt;/a&gt;, a
    state which is often interpreted as desperation. What&#39;s funny is that this emotion is not human, even apes may feel
    it.
    It&#39;s a feeling that makes losses have more painful effects than the joy when making a gain. This tendency slowly
    impacts the
    objective
    function as the person keeps making less victories, in other words, they would keep reducing their standards
    and lowering the bar as time moves on. As the standards keep going low, the human becomes blind against the
    potential red flags.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Is stochasticity beautiful ?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Real life is filled with randomness. In such environments, it becomes harder and harder to calculate your moves, let
    alone set
    a proper objective function as the number of dimensions grows exponentially, which is why some people study
    psychology. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Growing up in Morocco offered me an environment with tons of variables to deal with. On top of reacting to what I
    would see. To ensure my survival, I would still require something beyond the so called sixth sense. This is one of
    the
    reasons that motivate my coming to Germany, yet still, Germany also has some RNG to fight against but the
    probability
    range is a bit slim in comparison to my country. This is alluded by the fact that the law governs over everyone,
    however, humans are not perfect as entities, they might make some exceptions if they feel the need to.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As human beings, we try to minimize the luck factors by tackling the many situations using logical connectors.
    Initially, when dealing with randomness for the first time, the set of possibilities is \( \Omega = \{G_1, G_2, B_1,
    B_2.....G_n, B_n\}\) where \(G\) and \(B\) are a depiction of the positive and negative consequences
    respectively. Each element of \( \Omega \) has its own chance that ranges from \( [x, X] \)
    where \(X\) is an unknown upper bound to the possibilities that can occurs. As we keep learning about the variables,
    the \(X\)
    gets minimized, though it can never reach \(x\), one might think that they are safe, but you can never predict
    a wind blowing from somewhere and taking your most important piece of paper. Due to the unpredictable
    nature of living on earth, \(\Omega\)&#39;s set is always subject for changes. Altering the RNG range challenges the
    intelligence of the human. As they move forward, it slowly reshapes their problem solving, risk management and
    strategic planning... &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;One strategy to fight against the RNG is to join a community. People commit to build small communities where they
    share their experiences and expand each others&#39; knowledge base, which is often to be archived for existing and
    passed
    to the next generation. But what if those communities pretty much have no knowledge to back you up ? Job searching
    is
    one environment where you will often hear people say &#34;Just try your luck! and see if you can land a job&#34;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Job search, also known as: Recruitment hell, for a reason. &lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Job search is an environment where you can&#39;t concretely state a chain of moves that you can follow in order to reach
    your goal. It is subject to competition, the state of the economy, your expertise and even sometimes the mood of the
    HR...And many other corners that I am failing to perceive as we speak.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oddswise, the RNG set can be reduced to \( \Omega = \{Refused, Accepted\}\), this is true because of how
    imperfect the recruitment processes are, as you can&#39;t objectively make a guide that
    leads you to victory. Getting accepted would have you flip a coin against every obstacle, fail once and you&#39;re out,
    and thus the following describes the odds of both
    outcomes, where \(n\) is the number of the \(n\)th job application obstacle (First meeting, Interviews...etc..) that
    the applicant has to deal with and \(P\) is
    the probability chance, namely \(P_{r,n}\) is the probability of getting refused at the \(n\)th round:

    \[
    Refusal = P_{r,n} \quad \forall \quad n \in N

    \]

    \[
    Acceptance = \prod\limits_{n \in N}{1- P_{r,n}}
    \]
    \[
    \quad n &gt; 0
    \]


&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because of how limited our POV, as job seekers, we would prefer to hear the opinions of a professional, since their
    reputation is often succeeded by cutting down the RNG upper bound by a huge margin with their advices. One such
    problem that encourages
    this behaviour is how obscure the floodgates that everyone has to deal with when applying for a job. The strategy
    is then to not only decrease the chance of not being picked up by a company, but to also turn the acceptance
    equation
    into this:&lt;/p&gt;



\[
Acceptance = \sum\limits_{k = 1}^{K}\prod\limits_{n \in N}{1- P_{r,n,k}}
\]
\[
\quad n &gt; 0 \quad k &gt; 0
\]

&lt;p&gt;Verbally, this means to flip the coins at various companies up to a number \(K\) of companies, where \(P_{n,r,k}\) is
    the failure probability of obstacle \(n\) at company \(k\). As long as one has the resources to keep flipping, these
    statements
    still hold. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Due to the stochasticity of this whole endeavour, sometimes you might receive opinions that might damage your
    RNG, what&#39;s worse is that you can&#39;t really tell. Like when someone told me to remove the picture from my resume,
    saying
    that it&#39;s unnecessary. While the latter is true in the US, I was later told by many experts that this is not the
    case
    in Germany. &lt;/p&gt;




&lt;p&gt;It sucks that the orthodox ways of sending an application nowadays tend to lead to bad results from what I heard.
    This sadly impacts the mental health of anyone outside the loop. As people become slowly desperate, they slowly
    discover new
    tactics to add to their action set, like reaching out directly to an HR, or getting connected through a network.
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;As the duration of unemployment persists, you might feel a sense of financial urgency, which would push you
    to use any opportunity to secure the money and keep surviving. Depending on how sensitive you feel towards losses, and together
    with prolonged unemployment, loss aversion will make any job look like a royalty, even in a place with high turnover
    rates and bad reputations. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As of the writing of this article, many companies are slowly embedding artificial intelligence as an automation
    obstacle
    against the high number of applications that are attempting to net an interview. I am failing to see if this
    will kill the HR positions, though I&#39;ll still be interested in seeing the upcoming shitstorms.
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;h3&gt;Seeking a roof: the worst they can say is no&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
    August 2022 marks the day I was told that my old home was sold and that I (we) had till December 2022 to leave the
    apartment. By this time, a war happened in the east of Europe, which negatively impacted the economy and the
    demographic stats in the west, something which also played a role in making it extra hard for me to seek a new home.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Small spoiler here: I could stay despite the limit, but I was operating under some horrible living conditions, which
    make me
    and many question how I could still survive for that long. Hearing the news from the house owner motivated me to
    look
    for a better place after living there for aprox. 2 years. So even though I had the option to stay, this whole thing
    made me feel desperate for a new roof.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unlike Job seeking, the randomness here felt less punishing so to speak, as I could somehow sight the obstacles.
    Ideally I would prefer to live with the right people to maximize my survivability. Sadly I had to deal with the
    sudden demographic explosion, inflation, and some other unseen features that I will soon discuss and talk about.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Naturally, as a student, my options -In theory- were a bit vast, since I had access to services that welcome students
    much more
    than regulars. I had budget constraints, and I also had to wisely pick the people that I would live with.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Winter was approaching, I had to be active, as pretty much anyone who posts online about having a free room tends
    to receive tons of notifications, it makes me wonder how I would deal with it if I was in their position. The more
    I kept failing to find a place, the more I slowly kept increasing my budget threshold. I also had to deal with
    scammers,
    which sadly do exist and will for certain take any chance to scheme on me. The best I could do was to set an
    automation
    mechanism that sends a message to everyone who posts online right when their room goes available.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I mentioned that I would have to seek people to live with, though I did not mention anything regarding
    being compatible with them. This was a bit problematic, since I would have to mask in order to receive a chance
    at being accepted. Some would love to party all day, some would love to try my dishes....And there is me, who just
    wants to
    routinely be a student.
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/movie_seating.png&#34;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:center; color:grey; font-size:14px;&#34;&gt;Source: https://xkcd.com/173/&lt;/p&gt;





&lt;p&gt;There is of course, the other option of networking yourself out in order to find a clique to live with, an option
    that sadly wasn&#39;t available for me at the time since I barely built any relationships in my first 2 years of living
    in
    Germany.
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Mathematically speaking, with the way I see it, \(\Omega\)&#39;s space here only has 2 coins at the minimum, the first of
    which revolves around finding an offer and getting into contact with the owner, and the second is getting the deal.
    I honestly wish if some offers had a highly-detailed check list that could help me filter my search, or get filtered
    of course.
    But I suppose some might cheat this, given how dire the housing situation was back then.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the time of November, loss aversion started to kick in and I was tilting between accepting scams or enduring
    the life that I was having. Every time I came back home, the house and its people remind me of how stupid I am
    for not accepting an apartment room where I would pay thrice as much as what I usually to give each month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am writing this article from my new home, in a room bigger than the kitchen I had. Had I not asked an acquittance
    of
    mine for help,
    I probably would never be able to blog this out. My link to this person was purely professional. Normally, getting
    in
    here
    would require me to meet certain requirements, and receiving the privilege from this person was something I would
    never expect. I would never forget this and I would always be thankful for it. &lt;/p&gt;


&lt;h3&gt;Getting the European visa: My least favourite casino&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&#39;t have much to say here, this is somehow comparable to job seeking. Since you are dealing with unseen variables
    which somehow led to many into creating phantasies on the topic.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Normally, to apply for a European visa, I would have to submit my documents and see the magic happen. More often than
    not,
    getting a refusal
    comes dry with no feedback or remarks that hint towards the decision, which is why people keep speculating on the
    matter, to the point that I heard things like: Make sure to smile properly in order to have a chance.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without the feedback, it becomes a bit difficult to plan your next moves, especially if you are desperate and
    want to alter the outcome RNG. The wisest thing one can do is to have a plan B on the side. I recall hearing someone
    sold their house to generate enough money for the whole gamble, only for them to get a refusal.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In all fairness, this is a special case in my opinion, as all you have to do is to fill their requirements I suppose.
    I believe any amount of extra effort is great. I made it in by simply meeting the (official) bar, which is the case
    for many other.
    But some who had much brighter profiles couldn&#39;t make it, for reasons that are left unknown to us of course.
    Our society&#39;s psyche makes the whole thing discouraging when commenting on the latter case, where they would mention
    things like
    &#34;See ? his grades are quite high and still could not make it.&#34;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is of course, the idea that the feedback element is left unseen to allow for more money-farming
    shenanigans by the shadow people. The only way to find out I guess is to join their ranks and climb their hierarchy.
    This whole model has only one coin to be flipped, you either make it in or not, unless if you are into conspiracies
    which makes your sample space grow further.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the summer of 2019, parallel to waiting for a response, I was climbing the leaderboards of a competitive activity.
    My rank was stuck in its spot as I could not improve it. Amongst the members of my team, my rank was the worst. One
    of my team mates gave birth to the joke &#34;You have higher chances to
    get a visa to Europe than reaching our rank&#34;, a quote which I always laugh at, alluding that I will never reach that
    rank. One day we played together 2 matches, both of which
    were victories, and the second of which allowed me to reach the rank that I was dreaming of. After exactly 9
    minutes, I received a call from the visa office, telling
    me to come and retrieve my visa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Side note: The danger of living in a routine&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I highly appreciate structure routines. Under normal conditions, spending my days feels like meditating, as
    I have nothing to worry about, as long as I take the proper measures and as long as I stay responsible with things
    like
    paying bills and being on time with my appointments. It really
    feels good to be ignorant and face everything as I plan, I feel elegant and smooth in this state.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Relying too much on a routine, passively makes me sometimes forget and undermine the uncertain accidents
    that can occur in my daily life. Though I do my best to stay away from these, I am not a perfect being.
    By developing a routine and staying in this meditation mode, I put myself on a risk, which can often lead
    to anxiety, which extends to ruining my processing powers and implies a decrease in my productivity.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As much as I appreciate all the lucky shots that I had in my life, I sometimes wish if I could systematically
    tackle many challenges instead of relying on any sort of luck factor in order to succeed. It sucks that not
    everything
    is written to the public in some instances and that people would have to use their instincts/intelligence to figure
    things out. Some people keep telling me about how every deal with another human is a 50/50 if you simply engage and
    initiate
    some communication with them. To me, it never feels like a 50/50, it never was linear.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
		<title>Skill transfer - Word to LaTeX</title>
		<link>applethal.com//localhost:1313/blog/st_word_to_latex/</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		
		<guid>//localhost:1313/blog/st_word_to_latex/</guid>
		<description>&lt;style&gt;
  a {
    text-decoration: none;
    color: yellow;
  }
&lt;/style&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Prior to my generation, I was told people would hold seminars and organize courses on text editing. Its difficulty is
  evading my sympathies, as I can not determine if it was worth it. I suppose getting a diploma in the area would grant
  you access to many administrative jobs. I kind of imagine that the goal of these courses was to train the dexterity of
  the hands, since these jobs demanded rapid document processing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I grew up with the AZERTY French keyboard layout, I am positive that it has a linear learning curve, still, I learned
  that the layout is one of the least favourite among many communities online. Transitioning from AZERTY to QWERTY took
  some extra mental effort. After 4 years of using a German QWERTY layout, I honestly don’t want to go back. I still
  however fail to comprehend the dislike. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Naturally, It was imperative for students across the globe to write assignments on the computer at some point. The
  default windows text editors back then were enough for the tasks, but they were limited to editing the texts. Some of
  these assignments would have the students plug in some decorations to add more flavour to the text in the form of
  images and word art. Microsoft Word was the go to for these purposes, it was easy to use and offered intuitive
  functionalities. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;I am glad I chose that assignment&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fast forward today, I was exposed to \(\LaTeX\) through an assignment that I had for the university and I was somehow
  sold
  the idea that it produces beautiful and professional academic documents. Most mathematicians that I follow online made
  contributions motivating its usage. Eventually, I started somehow to love the beauty of \(\LaTeX\) works, every time I
  saw
  scientific works done in \(\LaTeX\), I would feel a stronger desire to typeset something similar…Until I learned about
  its
  learning curve..&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;For the price of having high quality documents, I would have to create a .tex document, which isn’t a plug-and-play
  situation here much like with MS Word. On the surface, the structure and the coding part may look scary and
  intimidating, especially when making mistakes, some of which are forgivable, while others are quite punishing. Here,
  you would have to account for the many small details like the dimensions of the document, or you would risk having a
  teleporting tables or an entire section being deleted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having a template to work with allowed me to quickly grasp what’s going on without having to manually look up
  tutorials, since I would just have to create sections, cite references, and write some text. After playing around with
  \(\LaTeX\), I realized that it was made with some “automation” in mind, where for the most part, you would be working
  on
  setting up a workflow that reduces the amount of repetitive work, which may also increase your productivity as you
  produce long articles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learning \(\LaTeX\) took lots of patience, and honestly, it really paid off, because I could then transfer my skills
  to,
  funnily enough, HTML. And later, I was passively taught the idea that with such environments, everything is just a
  syntax play. I gained more confidence to typeset in \(\LaTeX\) the more I wrote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later I learned that you may use \(\LaTeX\) for purposes that are beyond writing articles, I used it to write my
  resume
  and even create some presentations. If done properly, both of which look very clean and organized. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you wish to learn \(\LaTeX\), honestly just pick any template and start with it. Keep doing mistakes, and search
  how to
  fix them. It is frustrating, it requires lots of attention and patience, but it really pays off at the end of the day.
  There are resources everywhere and they are all well documented. One package that might require more courage is &lt;a
    href=&#34;https://tikz.net/&#34;&gt;TikZ&lt;/a&gt;
  which might cause some headaches. I believe rolling in the mud and fighting through syntax hell contributes a lot to
  the learning effect.
&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2&gt;Questioning its worth&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is it worth it ? It all depends on what you want to achieve. \(\LaTeX\) is slowly diverging towards more
  accessibility,
  still, I believe with the right setup, you can ensure similar results just by using MS Word as well. If you google
  “reasons to typeset in \(\LaTeX\)”, the average response juggles around: beauty and handling mathematic symbols, both
  of
  which can be maintained by using MS Word. After all, what matters is to meet the expectations of your assignments, I
  believe the medium should not matter, heck you can even deliver your assignments on written papers and no one would
  complain, as long as it’s readable of course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of the writing of this article, overleaf (One of the most recommended platforms) is becoming more aggressive with
  their premium marketing, limiting many of the basic functions that already were available to anyone. I recommend
  typesetting locally within your favourite code editor. This process is faster, presumebly because your local resources
  would be faster than relying on a server to compile your documents. Happy typesetting!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
		<title>Pasta with onion sauce</title>
		<link>applethal.com//localhost:1313/recommendations/recipes/pasta_onions/</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		
		<guid>//localhost:1313/recommendations/recipes/pasta_onions/</guid>
		<description>


I was just roaming online until I hit a video that claims that the recipe is quick so I gave it a go!

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Contain the water in a proper heating medium
  &lt;li&gt; Boil water @ max temps
  &lt;li&gt; Put the pasta in the container and let it heat
  &lt;li&gt; Cut 2 onions 
  &lt;li&gt; Using a pan, fry them together with some butter
  &lt;li&gt; Cool the fried onions using some water 
  &lt;li&gt; Add 20 cl liquid creme to it
  &lt;li&gt; Add some salt, pepper and parmesan cheese to it and keep mixing 
  &lt;li&gt; mix the pasta together with the sauce
  
&lt;/ol&gt;

I can&#39;t believe I pulled this off properly on the first try, it was delicious and took little to no effort. I guess the algorithm blessed me today with a nice recipe, else I would be
consuming my usual stuff. I am glad that this was a success as it boosted my confidence for more! I lost the video&#39;s link but I have seen people hinting towards the possibility of adding meat or thun fish to it.
I still think however that 2 onions were overkill here, as only a big one would be enough, maybe this is a craft for families. I don&#39;t see myself preparing this unless I have more time than what the Gantt chart says, it appears
that cleaning the pan after eating took more effort than what I anticipated due to how sticky the onions and the sauce was. I think the main product of this entire thing is the sauce itself, which I can maybe use for other 
recipes in the future, not just pasta.</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
		<title>Divided by zero - Perfectionism</title>
		<link>applethal.com//localhost:1313/blog/divided_by_zero_1/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		
		<guid>//localhost:1313/blog/divided_by_zero_1/</guid>
		<description>&lt;style&gt;
  a {
    text-decoration: none;
    color: yellow;
  }
&lt;/style&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  Since my early years, I lived in an environment where the best is meant to survive in the long
  term. As a child, my French teacher used to punish me for having poor writing by ripping off my paper and telling me
  to rewrite the texts, which were long and time-consuming by my standards back when I was a kid. Today, my handwriting
  is beautiful and praised by many, &lt;b&gt;but at what cost?&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Perfectionism is something that many artists suffer from. I can’t help it and I have to accept it as being part of my
  production process, it eventually leads to burnout, which is the cost of wanting to deliver the best of what I can. There are heuristics against it, but if you ask me, despite the
  outcomes, I like my final products! I like how I keep repairing the damages, fixing the errors, ensuring that what I
  present to the world is as shiny as what I foresaw during the conception phases. It is, however, interesting that it does not
  only affect my crafts, it plays a role in my conversations and interactions as well, as I often repeat myself upon
  wrong pronunciations. It often eats my time and makes me burn extra calories.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I am aware of it as an enemy; it offers the end goal of being satisfied with my output at the cost of my mental
  health. Had I not submitted to it, you probably would never see most of my works. Sometimes I give up due to
  technical limitations, though I try my best to achieve results that are &#34;acceptable&#34;&#34;. There is also the matter of properly setting goals; as a
  student, I had to write scientific works, and I always had difficulties determining what the professor is expecting
  from me in terms of quality. I often hear: “hey, you don’t have to spend that much effort”. The keyword here is
  “much”; you could say that I did not set a bar here, alas, I wish I received a list of detailed goals to checkmark, I
  disliked having this freedom in my writings, as it does not allow me to visualize what my person exactly wants
  quality-wise.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  There is also the matter of learning constraints, where I hardly accept skipping the elementary content unless I fully comprehend
  what’s
  inside, thinking that I might need to know it in the future pages. I suppose everyone goes through this out of exam-fears.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  I never attempted to stop perfectionism, what I do however is slow it down since I am embracing it anyways, as it
  allows me to see the potential improvements that I can implement. Once I notice a flaw, if it’s not critical, I add it
  to my to-do list and reserve a week just to make the fixing. Speaking of planning, I get triggered when something
  outside my influence breaks my plan and causes anomalies in my flow, so there is that as well.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  And even when things are fully done and ready for release, there is always a nagging figure that keeps murmuring my
  head about potential improvements, so I keep pleasing it so to speak. Sometimes this may lead to what people call
  “Imposter Syndrome”, which doubles as a feeling of loneliness on many occasions.
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;As a team member, especially if I am in a planning position, my artistic point of view makes it hard for me to
  be open to suggestions that I deem unoptimized, something which causes me often to be a bad team mate. It becomes a
  fight where my I have to reduce my ego for the sake of team work. This also challenges my charisma and communication
  skills.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In terms of interactions, one counter-measure against this quirk is to be honest, since planning conversations in my
  head tend
  to lead to some ache in that said head. I generally dislike doing this, but it&#39;s what society demands after all. In my
  experiences,
  some of my interactions had to be smooth in order to ensure my success. I recall a time where I was in need of some
  medical attention and being
  honest was sadly not a good option. Being honest and spelling the truth would surely reduce the complexity of my
  thinking, it sucks that
  there exist a set of unseen rules that are perfectionism-intencive, most of which revolve around me needing to fit
  into a world in order to
  dwell in these crucial exchanges. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It would be interesting to note though, that I learned about perfectionism as an idea at a very late age. Not only it
  helped to learn more about it, but
  I also learned about how some video game designs play encourage it by baiting people with virtual rewards.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;When money is brought to a setting where I excel, a new complex dimension gets added to my headaches. I have invested myself
in lots of artistic works, digital drawings, writing and painting...etc... I can not recall myself endulging in making a business out
of my craft. My awareness on the topic of perfectionism is the bottleneck here, by having to manage and deal with consumers, I would
have to actively put myself in burnout in order to satisfy their demands and surpass their expectations -Note that I used the word
surpass not meet- and let&#39;s not forget the invisible rivaly that I would have to fight through. Instead, I would prefer to participate
in these endevours by ignoring the money factor. Like so, I have the full control over my activity, and I allow myself to make the minor
mistakes, or in other words: I would do things while wanting to do them and not because I have to. By expecting monetary return, I might
become a pleaser, and the perfectionism devil would love it. It is natural for any business owner or employee to do their best in order
to keep the cash flow running, I can fully understand the mechanics of being part of this cycle, unless the person does not care about what
they offer to the rest of the world, perfectionism in this regard is quite hard to manage, especially under inflation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  Taking long breaks between each major output is essential for my recovery, without it, I would not have the energy to
  craft further. Not taking breaks has major negative consequences on the quality of my next output. There is also the
  matter of working on only 2 projects max at a time because having more
  can also lead to potential burnout, especially since perfectionism is on my side here.
  &lt;br&gt;
  To this very day, I still question my French teacher’s behavior, I am overall thankful that my hands
  were trained to write nice and cursive text, which extended to me being capable of nicely drawing. I am aware that her
  and my people had pure intentions, some say that they also had the same circumstances or lived lives they didn’t want
  their children to experience. At the end of the day, I partially do this to impress, as my creations act as a positive
  feedback gateway to satisfy my ego, knowing fully that what I made deserves the praise it keeps getting. Nevertheless,
  I will continue striving to reach greater heights. If you ever catch a mistake of mine, I will always
  respond with: &#34;To err is human!&#34;.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
		<title>Divided by zero - Consumerism</title>
		<link>applethal.com//localhost:1313/blog/divided_by_zero/</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		
		<guid>//localhost:1313/blog/divided_by_zero/</guid>
		<description>&lt;style&gt;
  a {
    text-decoration: none;
    color: yellow;
  }
&lt;/style&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;The general premise &lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt; As a man who is into tech, I love studying and learning about sofisticated tech solutions. I love my family and I want the best for them, yet I always had communication constraints with them, and all those marketing agents keep winning with their schemes. It&#39;s a two sided war where I have to fight in order to propose what I think is the best for my members, me vs marketing. After all, that&#39;s their job, and as a human who consumes, making decisions on what to purchase and what to spend my time on is crucial for my growth, both physically and mentally. &lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/marketing.png&#34;&gt;
  &lt;p style=&#34;color: #888; font-size: 14px;&#34;&gt;Been thinking about printing this on a shirt since the day I wrote this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p&gt;I think by the time I became an adult, I started to consciously divide between my needs and wants. I believe that growing in my environment played a role in this transformation. Once you list the functions of a product and map the right attributes to these, your perspective changes and you start discovering new options. Of course this thinking is not perfect, there will be points in your life where you are restricted by time. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did not fully read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.de/-/en/Unabomber/dp/1595948155&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Theodore Kaczynski&#39;s work&lt;/a&gt;, Although the book is heavily political, I think part of what the book contains aligns itself with my ideas. Before making a purchase, ask yourself: By using this object or service, how dependant will my usage be from any third-party ? Do I really need the object or do I want the object ?
 &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By analysing your decisions, you end up setting a search space instead of staying a prisoner of the monopoly. Let&#39;s take a look at a concrete example: When buying a phone, I often target the battery and storage specs, I set a budget and solve a 2 dimensional operational research problem. Because the tech allows for it. I would want a phone that allows me to use my storage, so no Apple products for me. Next comes the right to own/repair cultures into play: Will I end up freely owning my phone and toying with it i.e. Install any OS that I want ? How much can I repair on my own without seeking any third parties ? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another example that I saddens me often is when I attempted to introduce a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.raspberrypi.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Raspberry Pi&lt;/a&gt; as a medium that enables them to experience having a Smart TV, without having to own one. My family owned an old Samsung Smart TV, they believed back then that it could connect to the internet and allow them to watch youtube videos, which was true back when the software allowed, until an update hit it in the gears. I proposed the Pi, alas, they chose to buy a new modern TV instead. Raspberry Pis are flexible and there are multitude of guides on how to set them up for such emulation purposes, they enable more control over the device, heck I don&#39;t know much about the TV boards and I might start believing that every TV is a shell containing a small computer à la Raspberry Pi.
 &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;I hate subscriptions &lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we keep moving forward, marketers are doing their best to make it harder for us to keep our dependence, so much so that we took things for granted and normalized all of their schemes. Funnily enough this evolved way past media consumption and made its way to cars. On the topic of media, I like to own my music, I never pay subscriptions to Spotify or any of its similar software apps; funnily enough, not paying for a spotify subscription is beneficial to me: Since I am not subbed, they enforce an arbitrary song after playing the one that I selected; I use freemium Spotify, which is sufficient enough just for music discovery so it&#39;s a win-win for everyone! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Licences are also becoming more and more controversial, a recent Sony update made it so that people who purchased movies won&#39;t be able to eventually access the said movies as their licences are getting revoked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The movies and shows industry is having a monopoly-hell where many big providers like Netflix and Disney want to enable exclusivity. In this monologue, the marketing team plays around our patience. This causes yet another issue that I will bring up, which presents itself as a solution on its own: &#34;Backlogs&#34;. When a new movies/show gets released, if it coincidentally acts as material for something you have watched in the past, it ends up catching your attention, making you pause what you are currently consuming and get attracted to the new media and adding yet more stacks to your backlog. I am a patient man, I use my backlogs however to stall more time against my emotions and wait for the next chance to watch the show without having to pay for a subscription. This goes true for video games as well!  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With all that being said, my experiences translate as well in my computer usage. More often than not, it is usually the all-in one softwares that cost money, be it a video editor or any kind of software. What I usually do is to devise a workflow composed of small free tools that I can combine in order to achieve my wants. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Smelling the quality of a product before release&lt;/h2&gt;


&lt;p&gt;As I grew up, I developed a sense that allows me to see if a digital product is worth it, especially when it comes down to video games. Their prices are much more costly with some people justifying it as a consequence of inflation, which in my opinion is an idea sold by the people in the industry to normalize the prices. My years of reviewing games and software taught me how to grade a product and give it a price, so much so that it made me much satisfied with my consumption and made it harder for me to get disapointed. Some products are not worth their starting price that&#39;s for sure, so what I do against my patience is to create a routine of hobbies and check out my backlog while waiting for the prices to drop. Before getting into a game I attempt to future sight if I can finish it without getting bothered by my adult life and if paying for it will be worth my time and money, I am not gonna pay a high price for something that I can finish in a week. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could not develope however this same analytic skill for books and movies. Books are more baity than the youtubers online yet at least some authors do offer a small summary on the product&#39;s page which is to be appreciated. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;What&#39;s next ? &lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is where I am failing to predict the future, I know for sure that humans are becoming more and more aware of these schemes, and as a counter measure companies are pushing aggressivly. As of the writing of this topic, these greedy people are pushing for what would be called forced arbitration. I know for a fact that service sellers will always attempt to hide or decorate their plots, but for something like this, I find it funny that they are not trying anymore. Our data and its privacy are becoming sacred, I try my best to keep it safe, yet I am failing to sight the far implications of forced arbitration. I know it might push some customers away that&#39;s for sure, this will keep me curious for long. &lt;/p&gt;


&lt;h2&gt;But I am just a human being &lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My immunity against these schemes is strong, yet not perfect. Being into the DIY culture is something that I recommend to anyone, it teaches you self-dependence and patience.
Being a craftsman allowed me not only to save up some money, but to gain confidence that I can achieve goals without having to rely on anyone. It enables you to solve problems differently and passively makes you open to new solutions. Evil marketers are slowly trying to kill this culture by making it harder and harder for us to exercise it.  Years ago I would swap the battery of my phone and fix my screen without having to visit an engineer. Now, you have to visit the provider&#39;s engineer to fix your phone and still get charged for it, or else you void the warranty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/sticker.png&#34;&gt;
  &lt;p style=&#34;color: #888; font-size: 14px;&#34;&gt;Why pay for a sticker that does not even exist when you can make it yourself!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After all, some called me a frugal man and I highly sympathize with this, yet I can&#39;t allow marketing to win. They will keep creating their illusions and I will keep living happily ever after. They also mention that I this lifestyle slows down my exploration, all I can say is that my senses prevent financial disappointments. &lt;/p&gt;



</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
		<title>Chat-GPT Detox</title>
		<link>applethal.com//localhost:1313/blog/chatgptdetox/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		
		<guid>//localhost:1313/blog/chatgptdetox/</guid>
		<description>&lt;style&gt;
  a {
    text-decoration: none;
    color: yellow;
  }
&lt;/style&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prior to the Autumn of 2022, I heard about Chat-GPT and how some of my friends got private access into the tool. Back then I did not bat an eye, though I heard them that it&#39;s a good tool that quickly process data. I honestly did not care much until I heard that a friend of mine uses it for some of his daily chores. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I began using it right in the winter of 2023 when I had to rush something up, what I had was not perfect, it had some mistakes, which made me question its contraptions. After doing some reaserch, I learned that I came a bit late to the party. Right after it became a public tool, it was good, probably it worsen&#39;d due to it adapting to humans on a global scope, though it surprises me that it became bad at statistics of all things, a science where most of what you would need is to apply formulas and make interpretations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In almost every hall at the university, pretty much everyone had a Chat-GPT tab. Some professors were okey with it and said: Hey just use it for research. I think most of the students that I questioned used it for text generation, while some stated that they used it to generate facts. As for me ? I use it for debugging my code most of the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Funnily enough, I saw people holding seminars on how to properly write prompts for the tool. Maybe I am biased here but I believe these were stupid so to speak. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later on they announced GPT 4.0, an upgrade to the public tool that we used. It made me question if wether the company behind the tool secretly downgraded it to promot the former.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As time moved on and as I kept using it for some of my needs, I slowly noticed a big change in my life: Not only I started prioritizing using it over Googling, since it was faster at determining what I asked for, but I also noticed a gradual change in my patience vs. pretty much everything. It was the latter point that motivated me into considering this detox sort of thing. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I slowly started to lessen its usage every day. Not only it helped with recovering my patience, but also it amplified the learning effect, I may believe that it also improved my googling search querries. After a couple of weeks, I noticed my history containing no traces of the site, though my productivity has been reduced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Here is an even bigger question: Was this detox really necessary ? should one really stop using Chat-GPT ? &lt;/h2&gt;


&lt;p&gt; How would our lives look like if these AI tools never existed ? In all honesty, it depends on your purpose: What do you want from this tool ? &lt;br&gt;I think using AI for generative purposes has a negative effect on the learning process. I know it can be fast at handling requests, but at the end of the day, it becomes less fun the more you use it, especially if you love what you are doing. It&#39;s a double sided edge, I do however sympathise that the current economy and the current world we live in calls for its usage; we have an illusive need to solve problems ASAP.
Despite this, I still believe that these tools wrecked the psyche of our society. It poisoned us in a way that makes us depend on it the more we use it. Analog to what I said is when I noticed some students counting basic 2 digits addition in a calculator. &lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Today, I still use Chat-GPT, but only to give it headache labour, like giving it a huge wall of text and asking it to remove commas and put every element in an ordered list. In some rare occasions I would use it as a last option teacher in case I spend hours trying to comprehend a gimmick. My takeaway is, use it but be careful.  &lt;/p&gt;

</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
		<title>Simulated annealing for kids</title>
		<link>applethal.com//localhost:1313/sandbox/sa/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		
		<guid>//localhost:1313/sandbox/sa/</guid>
		<description>&lt;style&gt;
  a {
    text-decoration: none;
    color: yellow;
  }

  .tikzs {
        text-align: center;
        background-color: white;
        width: fit-content;
        margin: auto;
        padding: 20px;
        border-radius: 8px;
        overflow-x: auto;

    }

    .tikzs svg {
        overflow: visible !important;
        position: static !important;
    }

    .scroll-container {
        overflow-x: auto;
        width: 100%;
        max-width: 100%;
    }
&lt;/style&gt;

&lt;link rel=&#34;stylesheet&#34; type=&#34;text/css&#34; href=&#34;https://tikzjax.com/v1/fonts.css&#34;&gt;
&lt;script src=&#34;https://tikzjax.com/v1/tikzjax.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As of today and to the best of my knowledge, there are no articles that explain simulated annealing (Kirkpatrick et al., 1983) for those outside the loop. The terminology used in explaining the algorithm may be rough and intimidating at first. One cheap attempt nowadays to simplify the explanation of any concept is to go online and ask people to explain it to you as if you are 5 years old. As of yet. I personally have never tried this approach, so I can&#39;t review how effective it is. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We live in an age of accessibility, and I believe that simplify what is hard is the best proof that shows if you are capable of handling the topic or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Picture this: Imagine that just opened up a business and that you are looking for workers to maintain your cash flow. Consider that you are fresh into the world, by this time, your trust and naivety are still green. With that said, you will receive people with different backgrounds and different skill levels. Your trust levels are on top, and you will pretty much accept who steps at your doors. As your business keeps growing, you will at some point want to replace your current workers with some that satisfy your greedy needs, your current workers will set a bar, and as you keep encountering new people, your standards will rise and your trust goes lower, making you less naive and less accepting of those who might help you reach higher skies, despite their low profiles. At some point your trust in humanity will vanish, and your job offers will contain elements that are humanly impossible to achieve, unless the job applicants meet your conditions, you will receive no new servants, and this will keep on until you become the N°1 in the globe. Greed is good!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Naturally this algorithm is an analogy to metallurgy. It can be used to solve various problems where exploring a mathematical function is time consuming, most of these problems are of combinatorial nature (Traveling salesman problem, Job-shop scheduling..etc..). For a number of itterations, the algorithm attempts to explore solutions until it stops improving the objective function. Provided you have an objective function with high number of finite points, you can execute the algorithm and hopefully find the global minima, or maxima. &lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt; I know pseudo-codes look scary so I made this small diagram, sadly the standalone tikz does not support special shapes; the blue rectangles depict decisions, while the green and orange blocks are reserved for the termination and processes respectively.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&#34;scroll-container&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;tikzs&#34;&gt;
        &lt;script type=&#34;text/tikz&#34;&gt;
        \begin{tikzpicture}[node distance = 1.5cm, auto, font=\small]
    % Place nodes
    \tikzstyle{decision} = [rectangle, draw, fill=blue!20,
    text width=4em, text centered, rounded corners, minimum height=3em]
    \tikzstyle{block} = [rectangle, draw, fill=orange!20,
    text width=4em, text centered, rounded corners, minimum height=3em]
    \tikzstyle{line} = [draw, -&gt;]
    \tikzstyle{cloud} = [draw, ellipse,fill=red!20, node distance=2cm,
    minimum height=1.5em]
    \node [block, fill =  green!20] (start) {Start};
    \node [block, below of=start] (init) {Initialize trust T};
    \node [block, below of=init, node distance = 3cm] (getscore1) {Hire an initial worker};
    \node [block, below of=getscore1, node distance = 2cm] (getscore2) {Hire a new person};
    \node [block, below of=getscore2, node distance = 3cm] (difference) {evaluate the new worker};
    \node [decision, below of=difference, node distance = 4cm] (better) {Is the new worker better?};
    \node [decision, below left of=better, node distance=3.5cm] (trust) {Should I trust them regardless?};
    \node [block, below of=better, node distance=5cm] (accept) {Welcome the new worker, fire the old one};
    \node [block, below of=accept, node distance = 2cm] (decrease) {Decrease trust T};

    \node [decision, right of=trust,node distance=6cm] (dominate) {Do I have more patience ? Can I reach newer peaks ?};
    \node [block, below of=dominate, node distance=3cm, fill =  green!20] (end) {END};
    % Draw edges
    \path [line] (start) -- (init);
    \path [line] (init) -- (getscore1);
    \path [line] (getscore1) -- (getscore2);
    \path [line] (getscore2) -- (difference);
    \path [line] (difference) -- (better);
    \path [line] (better) -- node {yes} (accept);
    \path [line] (better.west) -| node [near start] {no} (trust);
    \path [line] (trust) -- node {yes} (accept);
    \path [line] (trust.south) |- node [near start] {no} (decrease);
    \path [line] (accept) -- (decrease);
    \path [line] (decrease.east) -| ++(1cm,0cm) |- (dominate.west);

    \path [line] (dominate.south) -- node {yes} (end);
    \path [line] (dominate.north) |- node [near start] {no} (getscore2);
\end{tikzpicture}
      &lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p style=&#34;color: #888; font-size: 14px; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;Figure: Simulated annealing for kids&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know for certain that adults would comprehend this diagram, I do however think that actual kids might not enjoy it, I just hope that they do not turn out to be greedy in their future. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;References&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;i&gt;S. Kirkpatrick et al.&lt;/i&gt;; 1983 ;&lt;b&gt;Optimization by Simulated Annealing&lt;/b&gt;. Science220,671-680(1983).DOI:10.1126/science.220.4598.671
</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
		<title>The making of this website</title>
		<link>applethal.com//localhost:1313/blog/hugo/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		
		<guid>//localhost:1313/blog/hugo/</guid>
		<description>&lt;style&gt;
  a {
    text-decoration: none;
    color: yellow;
  }
&lt;/style&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  Howdy! Independence is a hot topic in my circle; I always like to own my things. Since ages, I used to daydream about
  owning a private space where I can express myself without barriers and without being digitally homeless. Conceptualizing
  my website took lots of tinkering, and the more I kept looking for inspiration, the more my design philosophy kept
  getting damaged. &lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Learning HTML and CSS took no more than a weekend, heck it was super easy since I have lots of \( \LaTeX \)
  background, I think every student should consider investing a bit of time to learn it. HTML/CSS can be pretty much used to
  express pretty much anything, I remember seeing people online mentioning that CSS can be used to create lots of
  hardcore 3D animations, something which prompted me to believe that front-end developement is bound to the human&#39;s
  creativity. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although I have an artistic vision, I lack the knowledge set that is taught
  through these graphic designing courses, which sadly plagued my browser cookies and  ruined my
  algorithm for a couple of months. I wanted something simple, yet part of me always wanted to have much more
  customizability. Sadly, trying to match the two challenges my perfectionism, especially as a person who just got into
  front-end developement. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;//localhost:1313/old/test.html&#34;&gt;My very first design&lt;/a&gt; &lt;b&gt;(Warning: a song will play upon loading the page)&lt;/b&gt; was more
  than just a draft for my learning phase, I held an important emotional value to it.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;h2&gt;The header&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt; To begin with, I was inspired by those old school websites, which were very nostalgic and minimalistic. I planned to
  name it Applethal&#39;s junkyard. I used &lt;a href=&#34;https://color.adobe.com/create/color-wheel&#34;&gt;Adobe&#39;s colour wheel&lt;/a&gt; to pick the colors that work well with my taste.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/old/screenshots/header.png&#34;&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:center; color:grey; font-size:14px;&#34;&gt;The original header&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;First let&#39;s discuss the font, I chose &lt;i&gt;PT Sans&lt;/i&gt;, I discovered it as I was writing my first scientific homeworks
  for the university since it was imposed upon us. I liked how compact and simple it looks. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The background&#39;s colours were recommended by &lt;a href=&#34;https://color.adobe.com/de/create/color-wheel&#34;&gt;Adobe&#39;s color
    wheel&lt;/a&gt;, since my favourite color is the dark Grena (#753649). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The text on the right was a placeholder, it had the intended content. Clicking on the first sentence would redirect
  you to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=o1tj2zJ2Wvg&#34;&gt;Guns N&#39; Roses&#39; Welcome to the jungle&lt;/a&gt;.On the top left
  one may sight a song player, this one has by default plays &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Yz8ZNPICH30&#34;&gt;Melty
    Blood: Type Lumina - Waiting Room&lt;/a&gt;. I felt that this song would match the feeling of my writing style thanks to
  its relaxing rythmic loops.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&#39;t have much to say about the buttons, At first I thought about eliminating the &#34;About&#34; section but then I
  thought that I could use the section to advertise myself much better than giving people my contact data. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;The body &lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wanted a blog sort of things to act as the face of my website &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/old/screenshots/body.png&#34;&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:center; color:grey; font-size:14px;&#34;&gt;The original body&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; On the right hand side, you would see a small rubrique that has some of my online profiles, clicking on any of these
  would send you to my profile on their respective platforms. Hovering the mouse on &lt;a
    href=&#34;https://azurestrikergunvolt.fandom.com/wiki/Lola_(iX)&#34;&gt;RoRo&#39;s combat pod logo&lt;/a&gt; would spin it. On the very
  top is a quote inspired by &lt;a href=&#34;https://dota2.fandom.com/wiki/Invoker/Responses&#34;&gt;one of Invoker&#39;s rare
    responses.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the left, there would be posts which would spawn each time I... add a post... Yeah, they would have no other
  purpose. For exercising purposes, these would contain my insights and some small tweaks from the lessons that I have
  learned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/old/screenshots/body2.png&#34;&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:center; color:grey; font-size:small;&#34;&gt;Some Javascript schenanigans&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I want to direct your attention to the bottom post. I like &lt;a
    href=&#34;https://advancewars.fandom.com/wiki/Lash&#34;&gt;Kat&lt;/a&gt;, I wanted later to use that small snippet as a joke
  gatekeeper, clicking on any of these responses will display a browser message. Originally, I thought about making it
  so that clicking on the wrong answer would block the visitor&#39;s access for a couple of hours. &lt;/p&gt;


&lt;h2&gt;What caused the original design to become what you see right now &lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Working on the website while also dealing with other responsibilities led me to burn out, I took a break, a long one
  I might add.
  &lt;br&gt;After the summer 2023, I decided to give it another shot, while also revamp the design. The reason for the latter is that through out the time I spent surfing the internet, my designer eye kept getting altered. I ended up tinkering a bit more and decided to follow no trend, but to make my very own layout.
  &lt;br&gt;The colour palette are in
  harmonie with the ladybug insect, which is part of the gimmick of my character... Let me present you with a small
  linguistic lesson:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My real name Saad (in Arabic: سعد), depending on the context, means luck. Ladybugs symbolize that aswell in some
  cultures. Funnily enough I ended up choosing to deepen my studies in operational management, which uses combinatorics,
  probability and statistics as a basis. This decision has nothing to do with the aformentioned gimmick by the way, it was a pure coincidence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took then the time to research the appropriate colour palettes that would synergies with the insect and that&#39;s how
  I came up with what you currently see. Clicking on the lady bug enables dark mode.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; Things went okey for a couple of days as I kept editing the HTML and CSS of the website, until I made it to a point
  where I felt that there could be an improvement to my potential workflow, which would involve me adding articles here
  and there, a process which would take lots of effort with the limited knowledge that I had back then; and that&#39;s how I
  discovered &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt; on the 9th of January 2024! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/old/screenshots/huhugo.png&#34;&gt;
  &lt;p style=&#34;color: #888; font-size: 14px;&#34;&#34;&gt;How it started. For context SF stands for Street Fighter&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt; Learning Hugo was a bit intimidating. Going through the documentation used to spook me, until I contacted a friend
  of mine who was kind and offered me some of his time, I took it to observe how he navigates the documentation pages to
  get to what he needs. He could pull this off without having any prior experience with the framework itself, which
  hinted towards the fact that: All it takes is to read the documentation.
  &lt;br&gt; Hugo would suit the purpose of my website, since all what I will be doing is uploading articles and pictures,
  that&#39;s it!
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; Although their documentation was nicely written, I still had to deal with some barriers, namely the Go language.
  Learning some of its syntax helped me not only to deal with my needs, but it enabled me to add lots of gimmicks here
  and there in the website in conjunction with Javascript.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I could&#39;ve always looked up online for templates and used them, and even if I could manage to find one that appeals to my content; something kept bugging me in my head
about how &#34;this corner looks ugly&#34; or &#34;how this section is unecessary&#34;. In the end, I chose to make my own theme from scratch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/old/screenshots/buna2.png&#34;&gt;
  &lt;p style=&#34;color: #888; font-size: 14px;&#34;&gt;Not a street fighter reference, for once&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt; At first, I thought that I would be capable of achieving all of this within one night, and oh boy how wrong was I.
  The correct and healthy workflow would be to divide tasks and slowly progress through syntax hell.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt; Almost everyday, I would update my friend on my progress, as I read our past conversations, I would get some
  positive inner reinforcement that show&#39;d me the walls that I with his help could manage to jump... So much so that one day he said
  the following: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/old/screenshots/buna.png&#34;&gt;
  &lt;p style=&#34;color: #888; font-size: 14px;&#34;&gt;How it ended! Maybe I should make a fanart out of this interaction&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt; Overall, most of my activity involved me working on setting up an automation workflow, where I simply push updates to the website&#39;s repository and pretty much see the magic happens. I would like however to stress out that 
  my perfectionism has slowed me down for some time as I kept tweaking the system, once I notice a mistake, I impulsively attempt to correct it before moving forward.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; With that said, I welcome you to my website! I hope you enjoy the articles that I will be putting here! I would like
  to thank everyone who helped the making of this beauty, without their efforts, not only I would not be capable of
  displaying this article, but I also would
  not gain the experience and confidence to evolve as a person. It is important to build a structure and trust the process!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
		<title>Birth of a new hobby</title>
		<link>applethal.com//localhost:1313/misc/rust_gallery/</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		
		<guid>//localhost:1313/misc/rust_gallery/</guid>
		<description>&lt;style&gt;
    a {
        text-decoration: none;
        color: yellow;
    }

    * {
        box-sizing: border-box
    }


    .slideshow-container {
        max-width: 1000px;
        position: relative;
        margin: auto;
        margin-top: 20px;
    }


    .mySlides {
        display: none;
    }


    .prev,
    .next {
        cursor: pointer;
        position: absolute;
        top: 50%;
        width: auto;
        margin-top: -22px;
        padding: 16px;
        color: white;
        font-weight: bold;
        font-size: 18px;
        transition: 0.6s ease;
        border-radius: 0 3px 3px 0;
        user-select: none;
    }


    .next {
        right: 0;
        border-radius: 3px 0 0 3px;
    }


    .prev:hover,
    .next:hover {
        background-color: rgba(0, 0, 0, 0.8);
    }


    .text {
        color: #ffffff;

        font-size: 20px;

        padding: 8px 12px;
        position: absolute;
        bottom: 8px;
        width: 100%;
        text-align: center;
        background-color: #000000;

    }


    .numbertext {
        color: #f2f2f2;
        font-size: 12px;
        padding: 8px 12px;
        position: absolute;
        top: 0;
    }


    .dot {
        cursor: pointer;
        height: 15px;
        width: 15px;
        margin: 0 2px;
        background-color: #bbb;
        border-radius: 50%;
        display: inline-block;
        transition: background-color 0.6s ease;
    }

    .active,
    .dot:hover {
        background-color: #717171;
    }


    .fade {
        animation-name: fade;
        animation-duration: 1.5s;
    }

    @keyframes fade {
        from {
            opacity: .4
        }

        to {
            opacity: 1
        }
    }
&lt;/style&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://store.steampowered.com/app/252490/Rust/&#34;&gt;Rust&lt;/a&gt; is a video game that deserves to be a case study for those psychology
    adepts, it puts lots of emphasis on
    survival. Its core gameplay is to gather resources, whether it&#39;s by collecting, fighting or stealing. If you would
    pass by
    a stranger, their first thoughts
    are often sinister as no one trusts each other. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    Rust however was not a game for me, heck I did not even buy it to begin with, I
    won it in
    a
    fighting game tournament back when it was in its alpha, and back when I had a computer that was not capable of
    running
    it. Even after obtaining a new computer, I could not properly enjoy it on my own, and by pure accident, 2 of my
    people
    went into Rust to discover it, seeing how it had the fame of creating fun and moments of joy, moments which were
    very
    costly. Just like any PvP based survival game, enjoying the hours that you burn into gathering the resources is not
    free, especially since you are put in a stochastic environment: RNG seeded maps, servers populated with a wide range
    of
    people from the mushroom pickers and the pros who wall the PvP difficulty, the mechanics...etc..
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    I became the third of the pack, and as predicted, I had to deal with intoxicating idea of having to collect the
    precious
    metals and protecting them. By the time I started my first hours, I had no SSD, which was required to fight against
    the lags, something which prompted me to focus less on combat since my system was not capable of handling fast paced
    reactions, my role was then reduced to indoor organizing
    and farming the resources that we needed as a team, and in rare occasions participate in group scouting.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
    Although I had little impact on our growth, I still enjoyed hearing my team mates being happy about what they did
    despite my absence in the battle field.... Until I discovered one day that you can craft a wooden plate and put it as a
    decoration.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You see, the core gameplay obscured us from sighting these smaller features, &#34;greed is
    good&#34; some people said. Still, once I put one of these plates on the wall, my first thought was to use it as a label
    for our boxes... Until my boredom played its role and I started toying with the colour palette, which by the time
    was very limited
    for stupid reasons:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;text-align: center; margin-top: 50px;&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;../rust/colors.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p style=&#34;color: #888; font-size: 14px;&#34;&gt;The original rust colour palette&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Painting in rust was challenging, starting a session was spontaneous ,and more often than not I would have
    difficulties deciding on what to paint due to the limited colour palette and bad mouse tracking, and let&#39;s not
    forget about potential disturbance coming from the opponent players as well as my team mates if they need
    assistance. Ah, one last thing: Rust&#39;s painting module has no eraser, if you make one mistake, you either have to
    live with it or completly start over, and if you are an artist, you know where this is going... &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I kept painting and drawing, my dexterity kept improving and throughout my experiences I kept improvising. Some
    of these may look out of shape, though you might find some gems. Overall I am super satisfied with everything I did! The following slideshow
    doubles as a history of my slow self improvements.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;slideshow-container&#34;&gt;


    &lt;div class=&#34;mySlides fade&#34;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;numbertext&#34;&gt;1 / 33&lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;../rust/image34.png&#34; style=&#34;width:100%&#34;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;text&#34;&gt;The very first painting, this happened back when the Guilty gear strive trailer came with a
            reveal of May&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

    &lt;div class=&#34;mySlides fade&#34;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;numbertext&#34;&gt;2 / 33&lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;../rust/image37.png&#34; style=&#34;width:100%&#34;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;text&#34;&gt;Yang from Ruby&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

    &lt;div class=&#34;mySlides fade&#34;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;numbertext&#34;&gt;3 / 33&lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;../rust/image22.png&#34; style=&#34;width:100%&#34;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;text&#34;&gt;Heracross was one of my favourite pokemons&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

    &lt;div class=&#34;mySlides fade&#34;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;numbertext&#34;&gt;4 / 33&lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;../rust/image35.png&#34; style=&#34;width:100%&#34;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;text&#34;&gt;I ran out of ideas so I asked a friend for something to paint. Here is Mimikyu&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;mySlides fade&#34;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;numbertext&#34;&gt;5 / 33&lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;../rust/image31.png&#34; style=&#34;width:100%&#34;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;text&#34;&gt;Hsien-Ko is one of my favourite Darkstalkers&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;mySlides fade&#34;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;numbertext&#34;&gt;6 / 33&lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;../rust/image3.png&#34; style=&#34;width:100%&#34;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;text&#34;&gt;A discord user&#39;s avatar&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;mySlides fade&#34;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;numbertext&#34;&gt;7 / 33&lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;../rust/image2.png&#34; style=&#34;width:100%&#34;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;text&#34;&gt;I rushed this painting of Mika from Under-night as I had to go join my team mates&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;mySlides fade&#34;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;numbertext&#34;&gt;8 / 33&lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;../rust/image14.png&#34; style=&#34;width:100%&#34;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;text&#34;&gt;Mona Lisa &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;mySlides fade&#34;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;numbertext&#34;&gt;9 / 33&lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;../rust/image32.png&#34; style=&#34;width:100%&#34;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;text&#34;&gt;Tesse from Waku Waku 7, someone raided my base and I had to cover something explicit, thanks
            Gary for not adding an eraser &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;mySlides fade&#34;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;numbertext&#34;&gt;10 / 33&lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;../rust/image19.png&#34; style=&#34;width:100%&#34;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;text&#34;&gt;Kagari from Ikaruga has little to no artworks that I could use as a reference &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;mySlides fade&#34;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;numbertext&#34;&gt;11 / 33&lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;../rust/image9.png&#34; style=&#34;width:100%&#34;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;text&#34;&gt;Bee! &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;mySlides fade&#34;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;numbertext&#34;&gt;12 / 33&lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;../rust/image24.png&#34; style=&#34;width:100%&#34;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;text&#34;&gt;A rushed self portrait &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;mySlides fade&#34;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;numbertext&#34;&gt;13 / 33&lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;../rust/image20.png&#34; style=&#34;width:100%&#34;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;text&#34;&gt;I-no from Guilty gear&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;mySlides fade&#34;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;numbertext&#34;&gt;14 / 33&lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;../rust/image8.png&#34; style=&#34;width:100%&#34;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;text&#34;&gt;Es from the Blazblue universe&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;mySlides fade&#34;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;numbertext&#34;&gt;15 / 33&lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;../rust/image30.png&#34; style=&#34;width:100%&#34;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;text&#34;&gt;A self portrait&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;mySlides fade&#34;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;numbertext&#34;&gt;16 / 33&lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;../rust/image13.png&#34; style=&#34;width:100%&#34;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;text&#34;&gt;Back when Phasmophobia was famous&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;mySlides fade&#34;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;numbertext&#34;&gt;17 / 33&lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;../rust/image1.png&#34; style=&#34;width:100%&#34;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;text&#34;&gt;Iris from Mega man X&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;mySlides fade&#34;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;numbertext&#34;&gt;18 / 33&lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;../rust/image17.png&#34; style=&#34;width:100%&#34;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;text&#34;&gt;One of us graduated so we had to celebrate this with a painting&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;mySlides fade&#34;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;numbertext&#34;&gt;19 / 33&lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;../rust/image4.png&#34; style=&#34;width:100%&#34;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;text&#34;&gt;A new guy joined us, temporarily&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;mySlides fade&#34;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;numbertext&#34;&gt;20 / 33&lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;../rust/image12.png&#34; style=&#34;width:100%&#34;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;text&#34;&gt;I was working on painting neco arc until someone rushed through my doors&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;mySlides fade&#34;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;numbertext&#34;&gt;21 / 33&lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;../rust/image6.png&#34; style=&#34;width:100%&#34;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;text&#34;&gt;I hold lots of emotional value towards this one, I worked on protecting it for 4 days a row
        &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;mySlides fade&#34;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;numbertext&#34;&gt;22 / 33&lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;../rust/image26.png&#34; style=&#34;width:100%&#34;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;text&#34;&gt;I just realized that the quote does not stem from Opeth to begin with, but from Kakatonia
        &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;mySlides fade&#34;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;numbertext&#34;&gt;23 / 33&lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;../rust/image15.png&#34; style=&#34;width:100%&#34;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;text&#34;&gt;I invested lots of focus on this one and I am super satisfied, especially since I could pull
            this off without an eraser and on the first try&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;mySlides fade&#34;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;numbertext&#34;&gt;24 / 33&lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;../rust/image16.png&#34; style=&#34;width:100%&#34;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;text&#34;&gt;RoRo muse mode from Luminous avenger IX&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;mySlides fade&#34;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;numbertext&#34;&gt;25 / 33&lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;../rust/image25.png&#34; style=&#34;width:100%&#34;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;text&#34;&gt;RoRo combat pod mode from Luminous avenger IX &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;mySlides fade&#34;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;numbertext&#34;&gt;26 / 33&lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;../rust/image11.png&#34; style=&#34;width:100%&#34;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;text&#34;&gt;Kat from Advance wars &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;mySlides fade&#34;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;numbertext&#34;&gt;27 / 33&lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;../rust/image28.png&#34; style=&#34;width:100%&#34;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;text&#34;&gt;An artwork that I am proud of &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;mySlides fade&#34;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;numbertext&#34;&gt;28 / 33&lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;../rust/image29.png&#34; style=&#34;width:100%&#34;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;text&#34;&gt;This was done inside a cave &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;mySlides fade&#34;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;numbertext&#34;&gt;29 / 33&lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;../rust/image27.png&#34; style=&#34;width:100%&#34;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;text&#34;&gt;Yet another rushed one &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;mySlides fade&#34;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;numbertext&#34;&gt;30 / 33&lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;../rust/image23.png&#34; style=&#34;width:100%&#34;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;text&#34;&gt;Neco me &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;mySlides fade&#34;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;numbertext&#34;&gt;31 / 33&lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;../rust/image33.png&#34; style=&#34;width:100%&#34;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;text&#34;&gt;Tomoko from Watamote&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;mySlides fade&#34;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;numbertext&#34;&gt;32 / 33&lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;../rust/image39.png&#34; style=&#34;width:100%&#34;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;text&#34;&gt;Took some time, I am happy with this!&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;mySlides fade&#34;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;numbertext&#34;&gt;33 / 33&lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;../rust/image38.png&#34; style=&#34;width:100%&#34;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;text&#34;&gt;Pucca X Snoopy&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;



    &lt;a class=&#34;prev&#34; onclick=&#34;plusSlides(-1)&#34;&gt;&amp;#10094;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a class=&#34;next&#34; onclick=&#34;plusSlides(1)&#34;&gt;&amp;#10095;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;span class=&#34;dot&#34; onclick=&#34;currentSlide(1)&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&#34;dot&#34; onclick=&#34;currentSlide(2)&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&#34;dot&#34; onclick=&#34;currentSlide(3)&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&#34;dot&#34; onclick=&#34;currentSlide(4)&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&#34;dot&#34; onclick=&#34;currentSlide(5)&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&#34;dot&#34; onclick=&#34;currentSlide(6)&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&#34;dot&#34; onclick=&#34;currentSlide(7)&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&#34;dot&#34; onclick=&#34;currentSlide(8)&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&#34;dot&#34; onclick=&#34;currentSlide(9)&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&#34;dot&#34; onclick=&#34;currentSlide(10)&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&#34;dot&#34; onclick=&#34;currentSlide(11)&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&#34;dot&#34; onclick=&#34;currentSlide(12)&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&#34;dot&#34; onclick=&#34;currentSlide(13)&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&#34;dot&#34; onclick=&#34;currentSlide(14)&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&#34;dot&#34; onclick=&#34;currentSlide(15)&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&#34;dot&#34; onclick=&#34;currentSlide(16)&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&#34;dot&#34; onclick=&#34;currentSlide(17)&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&#34;dot&#34; onclick=&#34;currentSlide(18)&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&#34;dot&#34; onclick=&#34;currentSlide(19)&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&#34;dot&#34; onclick=&#34;currentSlide(20)&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&#34;dot&#34; onclick=&#34;currentSlide(21)&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&#34;dot&#34; onclick=&#34;currentSlide(22)&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&#34;dot&#34; onclick=&#34;currentSlide(23)&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&#34;dot&#34; onclick=&#34;currentSlide(24)&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&#34;dot&#34; onclick=&#34;currentSlide(25)&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&#34;dot&#34; onclick=&#34;currentSlide(26)&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&#34;dot&#34; onclick=&#34;currentSlide(27)&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&#34;dot&#34; onclick=&#34;currentSlide(28)&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&#34;dot&#34; onclick=&#34;currentSlide(29)&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&#34;dot&#34; onclick=&#34;currentSlide(30)&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&#34;dot&#34; onclick=&#34;currentSlide(31)&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&#34;dot&#34; onclick=&#34;currentSlide(32)&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&#34;dot&#34; onclick=&#34;currentSlide(33)&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At any rate, despite all of this, I enjoyed racking hours into this small niche of a hobby. I do recommend doing it
    in a proper server and not in one of those combat focused server. As of today, the only update that we could benefit
    from was a new colour palette, I am not sure how hard would it be for them to add an eraser, but since only a small
    purcent of people paint in rust, no amount of petitions would bring this feature to life.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div style=&#34;text-align: center; margin-top: 50px;&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;../rust/review.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p style=&#34;color: #888; font-size: 14px;&#34;&gt;Don&#39;t be this guy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;script&gt;
    let slideIndex = 1;
    showSlides(slideIndex);


    function plusSlides(n) {
        showSlides(slideIndex += n);
    }


    function currentSlide(n) {
        showSlides(slideIndex = n);
    }

    function showSlides(n) {
        let i;
        let slides = document.getElementsByClassName(&#34;mySlides&#34;);
        let dots = document.getElementsByClassName(&#34;dot&#34;);
        if (n &gt; slides.length) { slideIndex = 1 }
        if (n &lt; 1) { slideIndex = slides.length }
        for (i = 0; i &lt; slides.length; i++) {
            slides[i].style.display = &#34;none&#34;;
        }
        for (i = 0; i &lt; dots.length; i++) {
            dots[i].className = dots[i].className.replace(&#34; active&#34;, &#34;&#34;);
        }
        slides[slideIndex - 1].style.display = &#34;block&#34;;
        dots[slideIndex - 1].className += &#34; active&#34;;
    }
&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;p&gt; This however did not end here, I could somehow transfer my skills and experiences to other games. In &lt;a href=&#34;https://store.steampowered.com/app/346110/ARK_Survival_Evolved/&#34;&gt;ARK: Survival Evolved&lt;/a&gt;, you can&#39;t officially paint on boards, you would need a server that contains a compatible plugin for that. The following is sadly the only image I could find. I will certainly try to dig for more pictures, but I suppose they are all gone:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;text-align: center; margin-top: 50px;&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;../rust/namielle.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p style=&#34;color: #888; font-size: 14px;&#34;&gt;Namielle from Monster hunter is one of my favourite monsters, at least they have an eraser in Ark&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Prior to &lt;a href=&#34;https://store.steampowered.com/app/730/CounterStrike_2&#34;&gt;CS:GO transition to CS2&lt;/a&gt;, you could draw on the map, but you had a limited amount of lines to draw, attempting to increase their length will result into the other end being wiped. Post some CS2 updates, you are no longer hindered by this as long as you are in spectator mode. Sadly no eraser is available because this feature was intended for demonstrative purposes I believe. In casual play, I often challenge myself to draw as fast as I can before a new round starts. It&#39;s a fun challenge that sort of hones your drawing skills slowly.&lt;/p&gt;


  &lt;div style=&#34;display: flex; justify-content: center; align-items: center; overflow-x: auto;&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;../rust/cs2_2.png&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;../rust/cs2_1.png&#34;&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;p style=&#34;color: #888; font-size: 14px;text-align: center&#34;&gt;So far I could only make these two beauties.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The premise is that, if the game offers me a way to sketch, I just do it and attempt to fight through all restrictions. Maybe someone has to make a list of all the games where drawing is a feature that exists outside the scope of the core gameplay.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
		<title>Things that I achieved with pride</title>
		<link>applethal.com//localhost:1313/misc/acomplishements/</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		
		<guid>//localhost:1313/misc/acomplishements/</guid>
		<description>
&lt;style&gt;
    a {
        text-decoration: none;
        color: yellow;
    }
&lt;/style&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;//localhost:1313/..&#34;&gt;This website!&lt;/a&gt; Feel free to read more about the making of this blog &lt;a href=&#34;../../blog/hugo&#34;&gt;here. &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;//localhost:1313/sandbox/scheduling/&#34;&gt;The cooking scheduling formulation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;../rust_gallery/&#34;&gt;This array of Rust paintings &lt;/a&gt; coming all the way since 2019.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.speedrun.com/users/Applethal&#34;&gt; My speedrun records &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
		<title>Pasta with cheese and sauce</title>
		<link>applethal.com//localhost:1313/recommendations/recipes/pasta/</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		
		<guid>//localhost:1313/recommendations/recipes/pasta/</guid>
		<description>


A classic, I am not sure if it has an official name but I often cook it each week since it&#39;s cheap and takes little to no effort from the human end. Any sauce would work with this; the extras are optional, and funnily enough, excluding them does not cut the makespan of the schedule.


&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Contain the water in a proper medium and let it heat
  &lt;li&gt; Boil water at max temps
  &lt;li&gt; Put the Pasta in the water and let it cook
  &lt;li&gt; Meanwhile, you may wash the legumes and prepare them for the cutting
  &lt;li&gt; Start cutting what should be cut, this is the step where you prepare the spices together with the onions, papkrikas and cheese
  &lt;li&gt; After cooking the pasta, mix it around together with everything and voila!
&lt;/ol&gt;


This is a basic recipe that every student should learn to cook. Note that some pasta forms have their own custom processing time, though on average it&#39;s between 10 to 15 minutes to work with. You shouldn&#39;t overboil it nor should you mix it while it is not ready (Unless your teeth can handle it). It&#39;s a quick fix for a lunch yet does a good job at filling my stomach while also providing me with the energy that I need for my evening training.

&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Feel free to adjust the spices and the legumes to your desires. Creativity fluids art, I am no artist in this domain, yet my people liked it, and so will I recommend it.
</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
		<title>Rice, potatoes and thon fish</title>
		<link>applethal.com//localhost:1313/recommendations/recipes/ricethunfish/</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		
		<guid>//localhost:1313/recommendations/recipes/ricethunfish/</guid>
		<description>


This fix stems from the east, my mom used to say that fish and rice are part of what makes Asia a strong continent.
Pretty much every Moroccan that I knew mixed rice and thon fish, since the latter was pretty much accessible -Perks of
living in a country with 2 seas-.


&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Cut the potatoes
  &lt;li&gt; Contain the water and boil it in 2 slots @ max heat
  &lt;li&gt; Cook the rice in one of the slots
  &lt;li&gt; Put the potatoes on the other container
  &lt;li&gt; Cut the onions
  &lt;li&gt; Mix everything together

&lt;/ol&gt;

I did not specify which spices to use here but I suppose this is not compatible with everything. Not only this is a
quick fix on its own, but it&#39;s also good for those who train on an active basis, the rice and fish combo contains lots
of protein and can substitute meat if the budget does not allow it. Somehow it tastes better under the effects of
hunger. You may also add some mayo to the mix, it creates a new level of synergy on top of the dish.

&lt;br&gt;
</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
		<title>Scheduling is fun!</title>
		<link>applethal.com//localhost:1313/sandbox/scheduling/</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		
		<guid>//localhost:1313/sandbox/scheduling/</guid>
		<description>&lt;style&gt;
    .scrollable-div {
        overflow-x: auto;
        white-space: nowrap;
    }

    .tikzs {
        text-align: center;
        background-color: white;
        width: fit-content;
        margin: auto;
        padding: 20px;
        border-radius: 8px;
        overflow-x: auto;

    }

    .tikzs svg {
        overflow: visible !important;

    }

    .scroll-container {
        overflow-x: auto;
        width: 100%;
        max-width: 100%;
    }


    .dark-mode {
        background-color: #1a1a1a;
        color: #ffffff;
    }

    .code-container {
        max-width: 80%;
        background-color: #282c34;

        border: 1px solid #3a3f4a;

        padding: 20px;
        border-radius: 8px;
        box-shadow: 0 0 10px rgba(0, 0, 0, 0.1);

        text-align: left;
        margin-top: 20px;

    }

    .code-header {
        text-align: right;
        margin-bottom: 10px;
    }

    .copy-button {
        background-color: #61dafb;

        color: #fff;

        border: none;
        padding: 8px 12px;
        border-radius: 4px;
        cursor: pointer;
    }

    pre {
        background-color: #2d333b;

        padding: 15px;
        border-radius: 4px;
        overflow-x: auto;
    }

    code {
        color: #abb2bf;

        font-family: &#39;Courier New&#39;, monospace;
    }

    .keyword {
        color: #c678dd;

    }

    .variable {
        color: #d19a66;

    }

    .function {
        color: #61dafb;

    }

    .string {
        color: #98c379;

    }

    .comment {
        color: #5c6370;

        font-style: italic;
    }

    a {
        text-decoration: none;
        color: yellow;
    }

    @media (max-width: 600px) {
        .code-container {
            max-width: 100%;
            overflow-x: auto;
        }


    }
&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;link rel=&#34;stylesheet&#34; type=&#34;text/css&#34; href=&#34;https://tikzjax.com/v1/fonts.css&#34;&gt;
&lt;script src=&#34;https://tikzjax.com/v1/tikzjax.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;script&gt;
    function copyCode() {
        const codeElement = document.querySelector(&#39;code&#39;);
        const textArea = document.createElement(&#39;textarea&#39;);
        textArea.value = codeElement.textContent;
        document.body.appendChild(textArea);
        textArea.select();
        document.execCommand(&#39;copy&#39;);
        document.body.removeChild(textArea);
    }
&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Notation &lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;span class=&#34;math&#34;&gt;\(
    i \in M
    \)&lt;/span&gt; : Set of machines



&lt;br&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;math&#34;&gt;\(
    j \in J
    \)&lt;/span&gt; : Set of jobs

&lt;br&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;math&#34;&gt;\(
    p_{i,j}
    \)&lt;/span&gt; : procssing time of job j in machine i
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;math&#34;&gt;\(
    C_{i,j}
    \)&lt;/span&gt; : Completion time of job j in machine i

&lt;br&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;math&#34;&gt;\(
    LST_{j}
    \)&lt;/span&gt; : Latest starting time of job j



&lt;h1&gt;Intro&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a guy who is very passionate about combinatorial optimization, and as much as I kept editing the core of my
    website&#39;s
    layout, I thought about adding some spiciness
    to my articles, even if it defies my minimalistic philosophies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Living here in Germany slowly and subconsiously turned me into a time-slave. Evil marketers did a really
    good job at putting emphasis on time, creating a need for
    goods and services that make me priorities being on time. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scheduling was something that I was a fan of, the goal of their science is to find the perfect sequence of tasks that
    meets a set of requirements. Their motives may sound simple but the average scheduling puzzles are \(NP-hard\), our
    current understanding on combinatorics encourages
    the development of heuristical approaches to tackle the the hardships of investigating permutations by offering a
    solution that is good enough. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cooking just began to slowly become an integral part of my life, my life style makes it hard for me to
    innovate, I just keep cycling through a limited set of recipes. Old habits die hard, at least they do. When I feel
    energetic, my dexterity goes top notch, enabling fast reactions
    and quick manouvers across the kitchen, but sometimes I just brute force my structures without thinking, which can
    result in a chunk of wasted time, and sometimes effort.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the theory of scheduling, if a given situation is properly formulated, you may gain access to tools that aid
    you reach your goals, without having to rely on any form of soft experience. This can be achieved by understanding
    the setup
    and trying to perceive it with intelligence, after all, the methods of logistics aim to exploit all kinds of
    information in order to fullfill an objective. I thought a lot about how to design a nice scheduling setup for a
    cooking context, not chaining tasks as quick as possible may cause your food to catch a cold. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After tinkering with lots of tools, I thought about simplifying the scheduling formulation in a way that reduces the
    amount of constraints that I have to account for. What I will be proposing is the work of an
    amateur, as of yet: \(P \,||\, \text{prec} \,,M_{j}||\, C_{\text{max}}\).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt; Small disclaimer: &lt;/h3&gt; This work is purely an implementation of the scheduling theory. My intentions were focused
only on seeing if I can pull this off with some Javascript / Hugo. Although it was a success, I need to add that you
should cook at your own pace. Just take your time and never rush things up!

&lt;h1&gt;The machines setup&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of the parallel machine and single machine problems, are positioned in the NP- and P complete spectrum.
    Precedence constraints are essential because you can&#39;t mix veggies before cutting them. the aim is to minimize the
    global
    completion time
    or else I would miss the train. There would be no heuristics here to speak of, just a direct method, specifically a
    list
    scheduling algorithm since it has been proven by &lt;a
        href=&#34;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/0167637795000577&#34;&gt;Shutten&lt;/a&gt;(2003) that parallel
    machine
    problems with setup times or precedence constraints can be solved to optimality with the aformentioned algorithm,
    Except it&#39;s not a list here that we are talking about but a graph of sorts: I will be traversing the graph and
    checking for dependencies as I keep moving forward until I hit the last node.
    &lt;br&gt;
    As for the constraints here is how I dealt with some of these:
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Preemption: Instead of stopping the machine and resuming afterwards, I made it so that it is treated as \(n\)
        number of phases, each of which will describe their states.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Setup times: These will either be modeled as a seperate task similarly to the previous constraint, or in some
        occasions I might just combine everything together as a single task. &lt;/li&gt;

&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;br&gt;My specs:
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Bauknecht oven with 2 slots&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Panasonic NN E221MM&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Schott Seran stove set&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Unnamed toast machine&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Me and my tools&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;The formulation:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before talking about the design let me define what a machine is. &lt;b&gt;Pretty much anything that processes a task on its
        own without any active moderation from my end.&lt;/b&gt; My kitchen is equipped with a stove, an oven, and microwave-
    all of which can act on their own
    provided
    I initiate them - As for me, I have my own hands which will act as a medium to craft the best of the best.
    Specs-wise,
    I think the machines and I are modern enough. &lt;br&gt;
    As for the precedence graph, I will not go into deep details on the chain of tasks unless it is necessary. The
    quantity of my
    descriptions should, in theory, not influence the makespan; micro tasks like &#34;breaking an egg and then mixing it
    up&#34;
    will be
    summed up as &#34;preparing the egg&#34; for the sake of simplicity.

&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;h1&gt;Example:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here I will be showcasing a small example of how to model the Gantt chart of preparing an omelette sandwish.

&lt;h2&gt;Tasks:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;

        Prepare the egg
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
        Cut the veggies
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; Cook the egg &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; Prepare the bread &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; Stuff in the bread&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Machines/Tasks set:

&lt;/h2&gt;
These will be the tasks assigned to each machine:
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Me = {1,2,4,5}&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Stove = {3}&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And these can be modeled like so, because you can&#39;t stuff anything in the bread as long as your eggs aren&#39;t ready:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;text-align: center; background-color: white; width: fit-content; margin: auto;


padding: 20px;
border-radius: 8px;&#34;&gt;
    &lt;script type=&#34;text/tikz&#34;&gt;
            \begin{tikzpicture}

        \node (1) at (0,0) {1};
        \node (2) at (2,0){2};
        \node (3) at (4,2){3};
        \node (4) at (4,-2){4};
        \node (5) at (6,0){5};


        \draw[-&gt;, &gt;=stealth] (1) -- (2);
        \draw[-&gt;, &gt;=stealth] (2) -- (3);
        \draw[-&gt;, &gt;=stealth] (2) -- (4);
        \draw[-&gt;, &gt;=stealth] (4) -- (5);
        \draw[-&gt;, &gt;=stealth] (3) -- (5);


        \foreach \i in {1,...,5} {
            \node[draw, circle] at (\i) {\i};
        }
    \end{tikzpicture}
          &lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will not attribute any processing times in this example, just picture an arbitrary number for each task for now.
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&#34;scroll-container&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;tikzs&#34;&gt;
        &lt;g transform&gt;
            &lt;script type=&#34;text/tikz&#34;&gt;
        \begin{tikzpicture}[scale=0.7]
        \draw[-&gt;] (0,0) -- (14,0) node[right] {};
    \draw[-&gt;] (0,0) -- (0,7) node[above] {};


    \draw[gray!50, dashed, step=1] (0,0) grid (14,7);


    \foreach \x in {1,2,...,14} {
        \draw (\x,0) -- (\x,-0.2) node[below] {\x};
    }


    \foreach \y/\label in {3/Human, 7/Stove} {
        \draw (0,\y) -- (-0.2,\y) node[left] {\label};
    }
    \draw[fill=blue!30] (0,0) rectangle (3,3) node[pos=0.5] {Egg};
    \draw[fill=blue!30] (3,0) rectangle (5,3) node[pos=.5] {Cut};

    \draw[fill=blue!30] (5,3) rectangle (10,7) node[pos=.5] {Cook};
    \draw[fill=red!30] (5,0) rectangle (8,3) node[pos=.5] {Bread};
    \draw[fill=blue!30] (10,0) rectangle (12,3) node[pos=.5] {Stuff};
    \draw[fill=red!30, line width=1.5pt] (12,0) rectangle (12,7) node[pos=1, right=2mm] {$C_{max} = 12$};


    \end{tikzpicture}
      &lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

Tasks marked with red can be shifted to the right as long as they do not introduce any extra time to the total makespan.
You can cut the bread anytime you want between the 5th and 7th
time mark. These are called tasks with slack times, or in other literature as buffer times. Their times are computed
using the following
formula:
&lt;div class=&#34;scrollable-div&#34;&gt;
    \[ LST(j) = \max_{j&#39; \in S(j)} \left( C_{i,j&#39;} - p_{i,j&#39;} \right) \quad \forall j \in J \]
&lt;/div&gt;





&lt;u&gt;
    &lt;h2&gt;Small observation:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/u&gt;
A couple of people pointed out that I was cooking eggs the wrong way, more specifically, I put the eggs on a pan and let
the pan do the rest @ 6/10
heat. Apparently the popular belief recommends against this, instead one should agitate the egg as it heats up using a
pressure
tool. If that is the case then this isn&#39;t a Parallel machine schedule anymore but a single machine since I would then be
actively
doing all the cooking, increasing the total time up to 15. Despite all of this, I will keep this mistake up there for
demonstrative purposes.

&lt;h1&gt;About the computation&lt;/h1&gt;


Using a solver is totally unecessary since our list algorithm has a complexity of \(O(V + E)\). The following
Javascript
snippet will be plugged together with a module that generates Gantt charts, for now I am using Tikzjax but its slow
rendering speed and its lack of CSS flexibility motivates me to seek another package. The code computes the Makespan and
outputs
the starting- and finishing times of each machine, all of which are calculated using the classic formula:
&lt;div class=&#34;scrollable-div&#34;&gt;
    $$C_{i,j} = \max\left(C_{i-1,j}, C_{i,j-1}\right) + p_{i,j} \quad \forall j \in J, i \in M$$
&lt;/div&gt;

The data is extracted from the recipes&#39;s front matter and formulated as a list that contains all the information that I
would need. Thanks to &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34;&gt; Hugo&#39;s&lt;/a&gt; flexibility, plugging in the input in Javascript
made me write less code.


&lt;center&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;code-container&#34;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;code-header&#34;&gt;
            &lt;button class=&#34;copy-button&#34; onclick=&#34;copyCode()&#34;&gt;Copy Code&lt;/button&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;pre&gt;
            &lt;code&gt;{{ $tasks := .Params.tasks }}
                &lt;span class=&#34;keyword&#34;&gt;var&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;variable&#34;&gt;processSteps&lt;/span&gt; = [
  {{- range $index, $task := $tasks -}}
    {
      id: {{ $task.id }},
      name: &#34;{{ $task.name }}&#34;,
      machine: &#34;{{ $task.machine }}&#34;,
      processing_time: {{ $task.processing_time }},
      dependencies: [{{ range $task.dependencies }}{{ . }},{{ end }}],
    },
  {{- end -}}
];

&lt;span class=&#34;function&#34;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;variable&#34;&gt;calculateSchedule&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span class=&#34;variable&#34;&gt;processSteps&lt;/span&gt;) {
    const &lt;span class=&#34;variable&#34;&gt;tasks&lt;/span&gt; = &lt;span class=&#34;variable&#34;&gt;processSteps&lt;/span&gt;.map((&lt;span class=&#34;variable&#34;&gt;step&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&#34;variable&#34;&gt;index&lt;/span&gt;) =&gt; ({
        id: &lt;span class=&#34;variable&#34;&gt;index&lt;/span&gt; + 1,
        name: &lt;span class=&#34;variable&#34;&gt;step.name&lt;/span&gt;,
        machine: &lt;span class=&#34;variable&#34;&gt;step.machine&lt;/span&gt;,
        processingTime: &lt;span class=&#34;variable&#34;&gt;step.processing_time&lt;/span&gt;,
        dependencies: &lt;span class=&#34;variable&#34;&gt;step.dependencies&lt;/span&gt;,
        startTime: 0,
        finishTime: 0,
        lst: 0,
    }));

    for (const &lt;span class=&#34;variable&#34;&gt;task&lt;/span&gt; of &lt;span class=&#34;variable&#34;&gt;tasks&lt;/span&gt;) {
        &lt;span class=&#34;variable&#34;&gt;task.startTime&lt;/span&gt; = Math.max(...&lt;span class=&#34;variable&#34;&gt;task.dependencies&lt;/span&gt;.map(&lt;span class=&#34;variable&#34;&gt;depId&lt;/span&gt; =&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;variable&#34;&gt;tasks[depId - 1]&lt;/span&gt;.finishTime), 0);
        &lt;span class=&#34;variable&#34;&gt;task.finishTime&lt;/span&gt; = &lt;span class=&#34;variable&#34;&gt;task.startTime&lt;/span&gt; + &lt;span class=&#34;variable&#34;&gt;task.processingTime&lt;/span&gt;;
    }

    for (const &lt;span class=&#34;variable&#34;&gt;task&lt;/span&gt; of &lt;span class=&#34;variable&#34;&gt;tasks&lt;/span&gt;) {
        const &lt;span class=&#34;variable&#34;&gt;successors&lt;/span&gt; = &lt;span class=&#34;variable&#34;&gt;tasks&lt;/span&gt;.filter(&lt;span class=&#34;variable&#34;&gt;t&lt;/span&gt; =&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;variable&#34;&gt;t.dependencies&lt;/span&gt;.includes(&lt;span class=&#34;variable&#34;&gt;task.id&lt;/span&gt;));
        const &lt;span class=&#34;variable&#34;&gt;lstCandidates&lt;/span&gt; = &lt;span class=&#34;variable&#34;&gt;successors&lt;/span&gt;.map(&lt;span class=&#34;variable&#34;&gt;s&lt;/span&gt; =&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;variable&#34;&gt;s.startTime&lt;/span&gt; - &lt;span class=&#34;variable&#34;&gt;task.processingTime&lt;/span&gt;);
        &lt;span class=&#34;variable&#34;&gt;task.lst&lt;/span&gt; = Math.max(...&lt;span class=&#34;variable&#34;&gt;lstCandidates&lt;/span&gt;, 0);
    }

    const &lt;span class=&#34;variable&#34;&gt;makespan&lt;/span&gt; = Math.max(...&lt;span class=&#34;variable&#34;&gt;tasks&lt;/span&gt;.map(&lt;span class=&#34;variable&#34;&gt;task&lt;/span&gt; =&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;variable&#34;&gt;task.finishTime&lt;/span&gt;));

    return { &lt;span class=&#34;variable&#34;&gt;makespan&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&#34;variable&#34;&gt;tasks&lt;/span&gt; };
}

const &lt;span class=&#34;variable&#34;&gt;scheduleResult&lt;/span&gt; = &lt;span class=&#34;variable&#34;&gt;calculateSchedule&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span class=&#34;variable&#34;&gt;processSteps&lt;/span&gt;);
console.log(&lt;span class=&#34;string&#34;&gt;&#39;Makespan:&#39;&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&#34;variable&#34;&gt;scheduleResult&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&#34;variable&#34;&gt;makespan&lt;/span&gt;);
console.log(&lt;span class=&#34;string&#34;&gt;&#39;Task Schedule:&#39;&lt;/span&gt;);
&lt;span class=&#34;variable&#34;&gt;scheduleResult&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class=&#34;variable&#34;&gt;tasks&lt;/span&gt;.forEach(&lt;span class=&#34;variable&#34;&gt;task&lt;/span&gt; =&gt; {
    console.log(&lt;span class=&#34;string&#34;&gt;`${&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;variable&#34;&gt;task.name&lt;/span&gt;}:&lt;/span&gt; Start Time ${&lt;span class=&#34;variable&#34;&gt;task.startTime&lt;/span&gt;}, Finish Time ${&lt;span class=&#34;variable&#34;&gt;task.finishTime&lt;/span&gt;}, Machine ${&lt;span class=&#34;variable&#34;&gt;task.machine&lt;/span&gt;}`);
});
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;









&lt;h1&gt;Can a better formulation beat my makespan ?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would like to see that, Everything that you have read so far was the effort of two days and is subject for
    potential improvements. For now I am happy with the results, though if I get any new ideas, I will surely imeplement
    provide updates. Feel free to submit an issue on the website&#39;s repo or send me an email and I will be content to
    have a discussion on the matter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt; References &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;J.M.J. Schutten&lt;/i&gt;, List scheduling revisited, Operations Research Letters, Volume 18, Issue 4, 1996, Pages
    167-170, ISSN 0167-6377, &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/0167-6377(95)00057-7&#34;
        target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/0167-6377(95)00057-7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;details&gt;
    &lt;summary&gt;Change log&lt;/summary&gt;
    &lt;h2&gt;11/02/2024&lt;/h2&gt;
    Conception added, every recipe now has a Gantt chart detailing the processing steps while aiming to minimize the
    makespan subject to a kitchen setup.
    &lt;h2&gt;17/02/2024&lt;/h2&gt;
    Added Slack times indicators! Tasks marked with red can be shifted freely as long as they do not exceed their latest
    finishing times!

&lt;/details&gt;</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
		<title>A bug&#39;s life</title>
		<link>applethal.com//localhost:1313/recommendations/shows/abugslife/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		
		<guid>//localhost:1313/recommendations/shows/abugslife/</guid>
		<description>



&lt;p&gt;
A Pixar classic, yet another movie that fails to bore me. Alongside Chicken run, my cousin gave me a VHS tape of a bug&#39;s life.
Of course as a child. I could not capture the hidden themes and messages that the movie conveys, as my perception was limited to
&#34;The good guys suffer, the bad guys must be eliminated, the good guys find a solution and the bad guys perish..&#34;
&lt;br&gt;
Either way, the more I keep watching it, the more I realize the pieces I&#39;ve been missing... It makes me wonder if the plot, easter eggs and scenes would
stay the same if the movie was made today.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Visually speaking, the movie looks really good even by today&#39;s standards, the characters look astonishing as the movie tries
to project the perception of an insect and how they see the world. The soundtrack is memorable and well done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I heavily relate to the main protagonist across the many dimensions of his persona. One could say that he is my comfort character.
Not only he, but pretty much every character was nicely written, as the setting is made in a way that humanizes the characters, giving
me that sense of familiarity.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;In a similar fashion to &lt;a href=&#34;../chickenrun&#34;&gt;Chicken run &lt;/a&gt;, the protagonists used unorthodox methods to
get rid of the villain, something which taught the child me to seek unconventional ways to solve problems.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Without spoiling much about it, I highly recommend this movie to pretty much anyone. It&#39;s a 10/10! &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
		<title>Chicken run</title>
		<link>applethal.com//localhost:1313/recommendations/shows/chickenrun/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		
		<guid>//localhost:1313/recommendations/shows/chickenrun/</guid>
		<description>

&lt;p&gt;Chicken run is a movie that I religiously watch every 2 years. My cousin got me the VHS from the UK back when I was a kid. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back when I watched it, my english was weak and my comprehension was relying on the visual feedback and the film&#39;s
    great soundtrack
    in order to try and see what&#39;s going on. As I grew up, I slowly started to understand the themes and jokes that are
    thrown here and there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wish if these movies had their own classification, because it follows a pattern where the protagonist (and their
    group) rebel against
    the bad guys by using methods and tools that the latter did not expect. Another notable example of such trait is &#34;A
    bug&#39;s life&#34;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    The mechanical logic in some scenes is crooked and could be labeled as plot armor, though it does not ruin the
    watching pace. I liked how the main characters are all rich with their personalities and how the protagonist fits
    her role perfectly.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have watched the English, German, French and Arabic versions of these movies and I think that the first two top
    over the rest. Alas, the movie takes place in Yorkshire, so expect to hear many lines in the Lancashire accent,
    which somehow soothes my ears every time I hear it.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I tagged this article with &#34;For kids&#34; since it is family friendly, but I am sure adults would surely enjoy it. I
    still somehow believe that the target audience
    are the teenagers if you ask me. It is a great movie that I would recommend to everyone.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
		<title>Introduction to Operations Research</title>
		<link>applethal.com//localhost:1313/recommendations/books/introduction_to_operations_research/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		
		<guid>//localhost:1313/recommendations/books/introduction_to_operations_research/</guid>
		<description>

&lt;p&gt;I don&#39;t have much to say about this book, it is very user friendly as it goes as far as containing
    the prerequisites that you need to grasp its information. It comes with many handy examples and figures to help you
    visualize the data, which is a huge plus! &lt;br&gt;
    It is so extensive that it makes me question if the title of the book is real.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I honestly picked it up for linear programming, yet it managed to catch my attention with all the extras it offers. I
    highly recommend it for anyone wanting to get into OR topics. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
		<title>Mathematics 📐📏</title>
		<link>applethal.com//localhost:1313/recommendations/resources/mathematics/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		
		<guid>//localhost:1313/recommendations/resources/mathematics/</guid>
		<description>&lt;style&gt;
  table {
    border-spacing: 0;
    width: 100%;
    border: 1px solid #ddd;
    color: #000000;

  }

  th {
    cursor: pointer;
    border: 1px solid #ddd;
  }

  th,
  td {
    text-align: left;
    padding: 16px;
    border: 1px solid #ddd;
  }

  .row-green {
    background-color: #333333;
    color: #ffffff;
  }

  .row-beige {
    background-color: #f5f5dc;
  }

  a {
    text-decoration: none;
    color: red;
  }


  .table-container {
    max-height: 300px;

    overflow-y: auto;
  }

  @media only screen and (max-width: 600px) {
    .table-container {
      overflow-x: auto;
      max-height: 300px;
    }

    table {
      width: 100%;
    }

    td {
      white-space: nowrap;
      overflow: hidden;
      text-overflow: ellipsis;
    }
  }
&lt;/style&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Finding resources to enrich my mathematical skills required me to pick through a wide array of choices. Grasping
  Mathematics requires visualization, which creates a feedback exchange between the abstraction and the human
  understanding. Sadly some sources lack this important element, making the learning process even harder. Here I will be
  posting learning material that I find nicely readable and accessible.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;The table is scrollable. &lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;table-container&#34;&gt;
  &lt;table id=&#34;myTable&#34;&gt;
    &lt;tr class=&#34;row-green&#34;&gt;

      &lt;th onclick=&#34;sortTable(0)&#34;&gt;Name&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th onclick=&#34;sortTable(1)&#34;&gt;Type&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Description&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr class=&#34;row-beige&#34;&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.probabilitycourse.com/&#34;&gt;Probability course&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Combinatorics &lt;br&gt; Probability&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;This is my go to for anything combinatorics related, it is very accessible and very specific to this area. It
        comes with exercises and solutions and does a good job at giving all the basics and things that you need.
        However, I still believe that their exercises could use some changes, I would still recommend it overall.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr class=&#34;row-beige&#34;&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Introduction to Operations Research&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Operational research&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Does more than introducing you to operational research, it has the theory, the exercises and it&#39;s easily
        accessible on top!&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;


  &lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;script&gt;
  function sortTable(n) {
    var table, rows, switching, i, x, y, shouldSwitch, dir, switchcount = 0;
    table = document.getElementById(&#34;myTable&#34;);
    switching = true;

    dir = &#34;asc&#34;;

    while (switching) {

      switching = false;
      rows = table.rows;

      for (i = 1; i &lt; (rows.length - 1); i++) {

        shouldSwitch = false;

        x = rows[i].getElementsByTagName(&#34;TD&#34;)[n];
        y = rows[i + 1].getElementsByTagName(&#34;TD&#34;)[n];

        if (dir == &#34;asc&#34;) {
          if (x.innerHTML.toLowerCase() &gt; y.innerHTML.toLowerCase()) {

            shouldSwitch = true;
            break;
          }
        } else if (dir == &#34;desc&#34;) {
          if (x.innerHTML.toLowerCase() &lt; y.innerHTML.toLowerCase()) {

            shouldSwitch = true;
            break;
          }
        }
      }
      if (shouldSwitch) {


        rows[i].parentNode.insertBefore(rows[i + 1], rows[i]);
        switching = true;

        switchcount++;
      } else {

        if (switchcount == 0 &amp;&amp; dir == &#34;asc&#34;) {
          dir = &#34;desc&#34;;
          switching = true;
        }
      }
    }
  }
&lt;/script&gt;</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
		<title>Model Building in Mathematical Programming</title>
		<link>applethal.com//localhost:1313/recommendations/books/model_building/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		
		<guid>//localhost:1313/recommendations/books/model_building/</guid>
		<description>

&lt;p&gt;This book helped me become much more fit in the domain of linear programming. It is super beginner friendly and I actually might end up recommending it over &lt;a href=&#34;../introduction_to_operations_research/&#34;&gt; this &lt;/a&gt; if you want to go straight to linear programming, as this one focuses on the latter while the previous book I mentioned offers more fundamentals. Its sommaire is well structured and I could quickly navigate to the content that I need without being lost in its pages. It contains various examples that can be sighted in the challenges presented in the industry.
 &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
		<title>Programing 💻</title>
		<link>applethal.com//localhost:1313/recommendations/resources/programing/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		
		<guid>//localhost:1313/recommendations/resources/programing/</guid>
		<description>&lt;style&gt;
  table {
    border-spacing: 0;
    width: 100%;
    border: 1px solid #ddd;
    color: #000000;

  }

  th {
    cursor: pointer;
    border: 1px solid #ddd;
  }

  th,
  td {
    text-align: left;
    padding: 16px;
    border: 1px solid #ddd;
  }

  .row-green {
    background-color: #333333;
    color: #ffffff;
  }

  .row-beige {
    background-color: #f5f5dc;
  }

  a {
    text-decoration: none;
    color: red;
  }


  .table-container {
    max-height: 300px;

    overflow-y: auto;
  }

  @media only screen and (max-width: 600px) {
    .table-container {
      overflow-x: auto;
      max-height: 300px;
    }

    table {
      width: 100%;
    }

    td {
      white-space: nowrap;
      overflow: hidden;
      text-overflow: ellipsis;
    }
  }
&lt;/style&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;When it comes down to self learning, videos often challenge my lack of patience, readable resources are a preference
  in this case. Everyone highly recommends learning
  by doing when it comes down to programing. In the following table, I will put together all the resources that I have
  used to shape my programing skills. If you work more on your algorithmic skills, learning syntax becomes nothing more
  of a chore. I am never in a rush and I am happy with my progression so far.&lt;/h3&gt;


&lt;h3&gt;The table is scrollable. &lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://leetcode.card.workers.dev/applethal?theme=default&amp;font=baloo&amp;extension=null&#34; alt=&#34;LeetCode Stats&#34;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;table-container&#34;&gt;
  &lt;table id=&#34;myTable&#34;&gt;
    &lt;tr class=&#34;row-green&#34;&gt;

      &lt;th onclick=&#34;sortTable(0)&#34;&gt;Name&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th onclick=&#34;sortTable(1)&#34;&gt;Type&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Description&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr class=&#34;row-beige&#34;&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://leetcode.com/&#34;&gt;Leetcode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Exercises&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Intended to help with preparing for interviews, I use this to exercise as it helped me shape my algorithmic
        skills. I do want to emphasize that there is no official way to know from where to start but I intuitively
        started with the easy ones.  &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr class=&#34;row-beige&#34;&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://runestone.academy/ns/books/published/cpp4python/index.html&#34;&gt;Python to Cpp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Syntax&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;I like how Python acts as a nice introduction to programming, when I wanted to start learning C++ for fun, I
        had difficulties finding a resource that helps with learning the syntax. This learning program, however, does a
        good job at that. You may start here but it, as of today, still lacks a chapter on Object-oriented programming.
        You can breeze through it in 5 days since it is aimed at people who are familiar with Python.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr class=&#34;row-beige&#34;&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.w3schools.com/&#34;&gt;w3schools&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Syntax&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;If you google a html tag or a css feature, you will most likely have this website indexed by google in the
        first page. They offer a wide variety of tutorials in various languages, though I believe they focus a lot on
        the syntax. It&#39;s a very good source to learn web developement or pretty much anything
        since they have a way to display the output of your code.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr class=&#34;row-beige&#34;&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=https://neetcode.io/roadmap&gt;Neetcode&#39;s Roadmap&#39;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Roadmap&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Finding the right roadmap to train your programing skills can be a chore with the amount of available information that you can find. Each has their own &#34;how to start programing guide&#34;. Being into mathematics passively helps with problem solving but it&#39;s not necessary a must-know. Use Neetcode&#39;s roadmap as a starting point, although it is interviews oriented, it&#39;s very structured and organized.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;script&gt;
  function sortTable(n) {
    var table, rows, switching, i, x, y, shouldSwitch, dir, switchcount = 0;
    table = document.getElementById(&#34;myTable&#34;);
    switching = true;

    dir = &#34;asc&#34;;

    while (switching) {

      switching = false;
      rows = table.rows;

      for (i = 1; i &lt; (rows.length - 1); i++) {

        shouldSwitch = false;

        x = rows[i].getElementsByTagName(&#34;TD&#34;)[n];
        y = rows[i + 1].getElementsByTagName(&#34;TD&#34;)[n];

        if (dir == &#34;asc&#34;) {
          if (x.innerHTML.toLowerCase() &gt; y.innerHTML.toLowerCase()) {

            shouldSwitch = true;
            break;
          }
        } else if (dir == &#34;desc&#34;) {
          if (x.innerHTML.toLowerCase() &lt; y.innerHTML.toLowerCase()) {

            shouldSwitch = true;
            break;
          }
        }
      }
      if (shouldSwitch) {


        rows[i].parentNode.insertBefore(rows[i + 1], rows[i]);
        switching = true;

        switchcount++;
      } else {

        if (switchcount == 0 &amp;&amp; dir == &#34;asc&#34;) {
          dir = &#34;desc&#34;;
          switching = true;
        }
      }
    }
  }
&lt;/script&gt;
</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
		<title>Sudoku Jumbo</title>
		<link>applethal.com//localhost:1313/recommendations/books/sudoku_jumbo/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		
		<guid>//localhost:1313/recommendations/books/sudoku_jumbo/</guid>
		<description>

&lt;p&gt; A couple of years ago I used to go through weekly ergotherapy sessions. These had the duration of an hour and aimed
    to sync my nervous system and bring peace to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Part of these sessions would have me go through a set of exercises, one of which was a sudoku problem. At first I
    thought that I was challenged by the session&#39;s time limit, and my psyche would often compare me with people online
    who seemed to breeze
    through these matrices at ease. I thought at first that I had someone to best, then it took me a couple of sessions
    to realize that this was never a competition, but it should have been exercised as a medium of focus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After I stopped dealing with these artificial difficulties, I began printing Sudoku problems
    from the same source that the therapist gave me. Attempting to solve these brought me some joy, especially after
    being stuck for hours trying to find the value of a key cell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;text-align: center; margin-top: 50px;&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;../Samurai-sudoku.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;width: 40%; height: 40%; background-color: white;&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p style=&#34;color: #888; font-size: 14px;&#34;&gt;Source: Wikipedia&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the spring of 2022 I bought the book from a book store and a new routine was born: Right after each lunch, I
    attempt a puzzle until 14:00. Sure, solving these in a small time frame does boost my confidence sometimes, but each
    time I get
    stuck, I try to focus and find if I missed something. Coupled with a drink and a podcast in my ears and that&#39;s how I
    achieve harmony.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; As of the writing of this article, I made it to page 255. After solving each puzzle, I grade my meditation and my
    intelligence, and if I am being stuck on a given matrix after 2 weeks, I allow myself to look at the answers sheet
    to borrow a number. These exercises help me often benchmark my concentration and train my short- and longterm
    memory, because by the time my imprisonement reaches 14 days, I can garanty 100% that I know the potential position
    of each number.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; My experience with this book was great, so much so that I always bring it with me everywhere. Not only it taught me
    the aformentioned, but as I gradually kept progressing, it helped me drop my ego, because the goal was always to
    enable to focus on a given task
    and enjoy it, something which proves how effective these were as a choice in the ergotherapy domain. I miss the
    people of the ergotherapy, I hope that they are okay.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
	</item>
	
	</channel>
</rss>
